Thank you.
谢谢。
¶¶
¶¶
I love you.
我爱你。
Thank you.
谢谢。
all right welcome back everyone to another edition of the ethereum protocol fellowship study group
好的，欢迎所有人回到另一个以太坊协议奖学金研究小组
this is week nine the research track and we are here with piper miriam longtime ef
这是研究轨道的第九周，我们在这里与Piper Miriam长期EF
member and he will be here to talk about some expiry things today so all things the purge so
成员和他将在这里谈论今天有些过期的事情，所以所有的事情都清除了
So I will pass it off to Mario here, and he will give Piper a little more of a proper introduction.
因此，我将把它传递给马里奥，他会给派珀提供更多适当的介绍。
Thank you so much, Josh, and thank you, Piper, for being here.
乔什非常感谢，谢谢派珀（Piper）在这里。
And as Josh said, it's been a while Piper has been contributing to Ethereum,
正如乔什（Josh）所说的那样，派珀（Piper
so it's hard to give a quick summary of his work.
因此，很难快速总结他的工作。
But he's been around since, I believe, 2015, 2016, contributing to various core projects on Ethereum,
但是我相信，他一直在2015年，2016年，为以太坊的各种核心项目做出了贡献，
the Python ecosystem.
Python生态系统。
So if you ever used things like web3py, Viper,
因此，如果您曾经使用过Web3py，Viper之类的东西
or for many years,
或多年来，
people have been working on actual
人们一直在研究实际
Python client implementation 3d,
Python客户实施3D，
which we already mentioned in
我们已经在
the week,
一周，
week six on the Python specs.
Python规格的第六周。
And yeah,
是的，
Piper just gave me more time to introduce it,
派珀只是给了我更多时间介绍它，
that's great.
那太棒了。
Piper has been also one random interesting fact. Piper has been one of the first people,
派珀也是一个随机的有趣事实。派珀一直是最早的人之一
maybe the first or the second actual demonstration of non-fungible token on Ethereum,
也许是以太坊上的第一个或第二个实际演示，
so kind of an inventor of NFTs, if you want to call it that way.
如果您想这样称呼它，则是NFTS的发明者。
And yeah, so after working in the Python ecosystem and contributing to various pro-projects,
是的，所以在Python生态系统工作并为各种专业项目做出贡献之后，
I believe three years ago he started research and development of the portal network, which
我相信三年前，他开始了门户网络的研究和开发，该网络是
will be one of the main topics today, because portal is one of the alternative solutions
将是当今主要主题之一，因为门户网站是替代解决方案之一
for the history provider.
对于历史提供商。
Thank you so much, Piper, for being here.
派珀非常感谢您在这里。
It's an honor to have such an orgy here.
在这里有这样的狂欢是一种荣幸。
more important thing, yeah, Piper is creator of what was originally called CDAP and became BPF.
更重要的是，是的，Piper是最初称为CDAP的创造者，并成为BPF。
He's the father of this whole program as well, actually. The study group is
实际上，他也是整个计划的父亲。研究组是
spin-off of the protocol fellowship, which was indeed started by Piper here. So it's an honor
协议奖学金的衍生，确实是由Piper在这里开始的。所以这是一种荣誉
to have you here again. And I have to say, so far, my favorite presentation format, the actual white
再次在这里。我不得不说，到目前为止，我最喜欢的演示格式，实际的白色
work, it's incredible. So, go ahead, Piper. Howdy. Audio good? Everybody can hear me?
工作，这是不可思议的。所以，派珀，继续前进。你好。音频好吗？每个人都能听到我的声音吗？
Cool. All right. So, I started making some slides, and then I started feeling like busy work,
凉爽的。好的。因此，我开始制作一些幻灯片，然后我开始感觉像忙碌的工作，
diagramming Ethereum data structures and things and slides. It felt kind of boring.
图表以太坊数据结构以及事物和幻灯片。感觉很无聊。
I hope that this format ends up working. We're going to find out.
我希望这种格式最终起作用。我们要找出答案。
There we go. So this is sort of mixed about the purge. So the purge being, you know, one of those
我们去。因此，这有点像清除。因此，清除是其中之一
sections in that wonderful image that Vitalik has made for us about all the different
维塔利克（Vitalik
research tracks going on in Ethereum. And the purge itself is kind of specifically targeted at,
以太坊进行的研究轨道。清除本身是专门针对的，
I had this wonderful picture in my slides of somebody vomiting into a toilet, because it's
我的幻灯片中呕吐到厕所里有这张精美的照片，因为它是
us just trying to get some stuff out of our protocol that, depending on how kind of words
我们只是试图从我们的协议中获取一些东西，具体取决于多样的话
you want to use, they were just mistakes that were made in terms of how the protocol was designed
您想使用，它们只是关于如何设计协议的错误
and things that we want to clean up
以及我们想清理的东西
because they're not working, they're wrong,
因为他们没有工作，所以他们错了，
they're fundamentally limiting us from doing things.
他们从根本上限制了我们做事。
I started drawing some shape
我开始绘制一些形状
of what the Ethereum data structure looks like,
以太坊数据结构的外观
but I actually want to back up even a little bit further.
但是我实际上想进一步备份。
There was an EPF, one of these, I think maybe a week,
有一个EPF，其中之一，我想大概一个星期，
two weeks, a couple weeks ago about Verkle.
两个星期，几周前关于Verkle。
Um, and there's all of this stuff is linked together in some pretty intrinsic ways, but one of the, but I want to kind of like start in this in this vertical context and work our way forward.
嗯，所有这些东西都以一些非常内在的方式将其链接在一起，但是其中一种链接在一起，但是我想像在这种垂直的背景下一样开始，并努力前进。
So, um, I didn't finish drawing a full structure up here of like what kind of you know, Ethereum blockchain data structure stuff looks like.
所以，嗯，我没有在这里绘制完整的结构，就像你知道的那样，以太坊区块链数据结构的内容。
But I want to talk about block execution and what happens during block execution.
但是我想谈谈块执行以及块执行期间发生的情况。
A block is full of this series of...
一个街区充满了这一系列...
You've got a block, and in it are a series of transactions.
您有一个障碍，其中是一系列交易。
And each one of those transactions gets executed in a block.
这些交易中的每一项都在一个块中执行。
and as we step through each one of these transactions it has possibly some like data
当我们踏上这些交易中的每一笔交易时，它可能有一些喜欢的数据
with it that we call call data and that call data gets fed into the evm uh the the transaction
通过它，我们呼叫呼叫数据，该呼叫数据被送入EVM uh交易
parameters like what address it is sent to dictate things like whether it executes a contract and
参数类似于发送的地址来决定是否执行合同和
most transactions there's a there's a lot of just simple value transfers and and those do touch
大多数交易都有很多简单的价值转移，而这些交易确实触摸了
state but most transactions are contracts and so they start digging down into the ethereum state
州但大多数交易是合同，因此他们开始挖掘到以太坊状态
And the Ethereum state, kid trash and drawings on my floor, the Ethereum state is a Merkle Patricia tree.
以及以太坊状态，儿童垃圾和我地板上的图纸，以太坊状态是默克尔·帕特里夏（Merkle Patricia）树。
And there are all kinds of ways that you can diagram these, and diagramming them for real on a whiteboard is a giant pain because they have 16 branches at each level, and that's a lot to draw.
您可以通过各种方式来绘制这些图表，并且在白板上对它们进行真实的图表是一种巨大的痛苦，因为它们在每个层面上都有16个分支，而且要画很多。
So often in any of my diagrams here, I'll be drawing things that look like binary trees, but in reality, think of each of these things as having 16 branches.
因此，在这里的任何图表中，我经常会画出看起来像二进制树的东西，但实际上，将每个东西都视为拥有16个分支。
The Ethereum state is this kind of like big monster data set.
以太坊状态就像大型怪物数据集一样。
We call it the Merkle Patricia tree, and it is kind of anchored at each block under this value that we call the state root.
我们称其为Merkle Patricia树，在我们称为状态根的该值下，它在每个块上固定在每个块上。
And under the state root is a tree of nodes that eventually find their way down here to the bottom where you get accounts.
在状态根下是一棵节点树，最终找到了他们在这里获得帐户的底部的方式。
And in each of these accounts, sometimes they're externally owned accounts and they have no concept of state built into them.
在这些帐户中的每个帐户中，有时它们是外部拥有的帐户，并且它们没有内置的国家概念。
But when they are a contract, each of these has a state.
但是，当它们是合同时，它们中的每一个都有一个状态。
And each of these has dangly bits hanging off the bottom.
这些都悬挂在底部。
Okay, so when we get into block execution, there's this set of transactions, right?
好的，当我们进入块执行时，有一组交易，对吗？
Each block has a gas limit, and that gas limit and the Merkle-Patricia tree and Verkle are all sort of tied together.
每个块都有一个气体限制，并且气体极限和默克尔 - 帕特里亚树和Verkle都捆绑在一起。
So Ethereum clients have this – so we get into block execution, and the code says access sim state, access sim state,
因此，以太坊客户端拥有此功能 - 因此我们进入了块执行，该代码表示​​访问SIM状态，访问SIM状态，
and we have to reach all over this massive tree, and it has trillions of values in it these days,
我们必须到达这棵巨大的树，如今它有数万亿个价值观，
it is definitely into the high billions. It is a big piece of data. And in order to do block
绝对是数十亿美元。这是一个很大的数据。为了做阻止
execution, what you're effectively doing is random access all over this thing, and it is a big,
执行，您实际上在做的事情是随机访问这件事，这是一个很大的
ugly data set. So some of the early implementations of the Merkle-Patricia tree started with what I
丑陋的数据集。因此，Merkle-Patricia树的一些早期实现始于我
often call the naive approach. It is the simple approach to implementing this in like a real
通常称呼天真的方法。这是一种简单的方法，就像真实的
piece of software, which is that they stored everything by all of these individual nodes
一块软件，那就是他们用所有这些节点存储了所有内容
inside of the tree. And if you wanted to get down here, what the client had to do was it had to walk
在树上。如果您想在这里到这里，客户必须做的是必须走路
through its database down here. Now, these days, the data set is large enough that to get to an
通过其数据库在这里。现在，这些天，数据集足够大，以至于
account, you've got to go about seven layers deep. So you've got seven kind of disk reads here.
帐户，您必须深入七层。因此，您在这里读了七种磁盘。
And then when we start getting into smart contract storage and things like that, you're going even
然后，当我们开始进入智能合同存储等等时，您甚至要去
further down into these trees. So one of the early bottlenecks in Ethereum clients was
进一步进入这些树。因此，以太坊客户的早期瓶颈之一是
this access pattern.
此访问模式。
So this access pattern alone
因此仅此访问模式
of having to step down through each tree node
必须向下逐步穿过每个树节点
as you went is heavy, right?
当你去的时候很重，对吗？
Disk access is pretty fast.
磁盘访问非常快。
You know, clients are using things like level DB
您知道，客户正在使用级别DB之类的东西
and then some people figure out
然后有些人弄清楚
that rocks DB was maybe like a little bit faster.
岩石DB可能会更快一些。
I'm not really sure
我不确定
if that's actually holds true these days,
如果这几天实际上是正确的，
but either way,
但是无论哪种方式
they're using these really fast key value stores,
他们正在使用这些非常快速的钥匙值商店，
high-speed SSDs, and even there, the bottleneck for Ethereum clients executing blocks was the
高速SSD，甚至在那里，以太坊客户执行块的瓶颈是
rate at which they could access this stuff. So fast forward a couple of years of hard engineering
他们可以访问这些东西的比率。如此快进了几年的艰苦工程
work, and what you get is you get new models of this data. So this has like an O,
工作，而您得到的是您获得了这些数据的新模型。所以这就像一个O，
I'm not going to get this exactly right, but it's something like O log log in access
我不会完全正确，但这是类似o log in incess访问的东西
pattern here, okay? It's expensive. It's cheap in terms of certain things, but it ended up being
图案在这里，好吗？这很昂贵。就某些事情而言，它很便宜，但最终是
expensive, right? You're talking about in some of the average cases here, digging through like
昂贵，对吗？您在这里的某些平均情况中谈论，挖掘
seven to 10 layers of tree data to get to things. And so this was the bottleneck. This was the
七到10层的树数据可以进入事物。所以这就是瓶颈。这是
throughput. So client teams did a whole bunch of engineering work, and they built what we call,
吞吐量。因此，客户团队做了大量的工程工作，他们构建了我们所谓的工作，
I guess, flat database designs that had just O1 access, which meant that for any key in this
我想，平面数据库设计仅访问O1，这意味着对于此键
dataset, they could generally just go straight to it, okay? I'm not going to get into exactly
数据集，他们通常可以直接去，好吗？我不会准确地进入
the specifics of how that design came about or how it's implemented. Go read some client code,
该设计如何产生或实施方式的细节。去阅读一些客户端代码，
go ask some client developers. They can talk to you about that. Not the point of this talk.
去询问一些客户开发人员。他们可以与您谈谈。这不是这个谈话的重点。
So this O1 access pattern opened up a lot of throughput, right? So before this,
因此，这种O1访问模式打开了很多吞吐量，对吗？所以在此之前，
clients were bottlenecked on this kind of like O log log in access pattern. And this effectively
在这种访问模式中的o登录登录中，客户端被瓶颈。这有效
dictates the overall block gas limit, okay? And the gas limit is sort of like an Ethereum scaling
决定整体块气体限制，好吗？气体极限有点像以太坊缩放
number, right? We're never going to get to like MasterCard visa transaction through puts by upping
号码，对吗？我们永远不会像Mastercard Visa交易来通过提高投票
the gas limit, but the gas limit does dictate how many transactions worth of stuff the base chain
气体限制，但气体限制确实决定了基本链的价值数量
can do. So, so we figured out a way to get from, from this access pattern of like, oh, log, log in
可以做。因此，因此，我们从这种访问模式登录，登录的访问模式中找到了一种从中获取的方法
to, to like a, a really nice, oh, one. And this thing gave Ethereum clients a bit of a speed
要喜欢一个，一个非常好，哦，一个。这东西给以太坊客户有点速度
boost in terms of how fast they could execute blocks. But even still, it ends up being that
提高他们可以执行块的速度。但是即使仍然如此，最终还是
Ethereum clients, to the best of my knowledge, are effectively bottlenecked on disk IO. Because
据我所知，以太坊的客户实际上在磁盘上有效地瓶颈。因为
even moving to this O1 access pattern, there are tons and tons of state accesses inside of a block
即使转到此O1访问模式，块内也有大量的状态访问
that gets executed. And the state access is very random access, and the state itself is very,
执行。状态访问是非常随机的访问，状态本身非常
very large. So what we would love to do, so what we wanted to do was say, okay, well, maybe we can
很大。所以我们想做的事，所以我们想做的就是说，好吧，也许我们可以
do this stateless thing. So many years back, we all got together and started working on what,
做这个无状态的事情。这么多年前，我们都聚集在一起，开始研究什么，
you know, stateless Ethereum looks like. And ultimately, what one of the main bottlenecks
您知道，无国籍以太坊看起来像。最终，是什么主要瓶颈
were, what was, the Merkle-Patricia tree. So the Merkle-Patricia tree itself ended up being the
是默克尔 - 帕特里亚树。因此，默克尔 - 帕特里亚树本身最终成为
thing that was sort of blocking us from being able to go from this kind of like the best that
这有点阻止了我们能够从这种最好的事情中脱离
we could do in terms of client design where they're storing all the state locally, they've
我们可以在客户设计方面做到他们在本地存储的所有国家，他们已经
got it, and they've got this nice O1 access pattern. But even there, with that being the
明白了，他们拥有这种不错的O1访问模式。但是即使在那里，那是
bottleneck for us to go faster, the idea was witnesses. So witness being a proof of all of
瓶颈让我们走得更快，这个想法是见证人。因此见证是所有的证明
the state that a block accesses. And rather than a client needing to read all of that state off of
块访问的状态。而不是需要读取所有状态的客户
it's disk it could just be given it and use that as the state data for whatever uh for uh for
它是磁盘，它可以得到它，并将其用作uh的状态数据
executing a block um the problem is that the merka patricia tree uh has really inefficient proofs
执行一个块，问题是Merka Patricia树UH确实有效率低下的证据
um in fact it's got even sort of like attackable proofs some of like the worst case proof sizes i
嗯，实际上，它甚至有点像可攻击的证据，例如最坏的案例证明大小
think when we looked at these numbers and i'm pulling stuff from pretty deep memory so
想一想当我们查看这些数字时，我正在从相当深刻的记忆中拉出东西，所以
So take all of this with a grain of salt.
因此，将所有这些用一粒盐拿走。
But to do proofs with the Merkle-Patricia tree meant proofs that were potentially in the tens to hundreds of megabytes.
但是用默克尔 - 帕特里亚树做证据，这意味着有可能在数十个兆字节中的证据。
And the reason for that is that branching factor of 16, that at every level of the Merkle Patricia tree, if you want to provide a proof to anybody, you've got to branch out to that.
原因是分支因子为16，即在默克尔·帕特里夏树（Merkle Patricia Tree）的每个级别，如果您想向任何人提供证明，则必须对此进行分支。
You've got to include all of those, like, possibly 15 sibling node elements in order to have a full proof for execution data.
您必须包括所有这些，例如，可能是15个兄弟姐妹节点元素，以便为执行数据提供完整的证明。
So this is where Verkle comes from.
因此，这就是Verkle的来源。
Virgo comes from us needing a different tree design that has a much more succinct proof shape so that we can actually do this whole stateless thing where we distribute proofs around.
处女座来自我们需要一种不同的树设计，该设计具有更简洁的形状，以便我们实际上可以在分发证明的情况下完成整个无状态的事情。
Okay. In the process of going towards stateless Ethereum, what we found was that like going full, we wanted to clean up a lot of stuff, right? Getting proofs was just kind of like one piece of this, where we had this big inefficiency, this big tech debt, legacy thing that we chose to use, right?
好的。在进入无国籍以太坊的过程中，我们发现的是，我们想清理很多东西，对吗？获得证据就像是其中的一部分，在那里我们拥有如此巨大的效率，这种大的技术债务，我们选择使用的旧事物，对吗？
Miracle Patricia trees were great.
奇迹帕特里夏树很棒。
And at the time that Ethereum was built, it was, you know, like,
在以太坊建造时，您知道，就像
Virkle trees didn't exist.
virkle树不存在。
Nobody had come up with them yet.
还没有人提出。
But then as we got further, we realized that there were things that we wanted
但是随着我们的进一步，我们意识到有一些我们想要的东西
that Miracle Patricia trees were holding us back.
那奇迹帕特里夏树阻止了我们。
So Virkle is one of these things that we've worked to unlock.
因此，Virkle是我们努力解锁的这些事情之一。
Virkle is maybe the thing that unlocks one of the things that we wanted,
Virkle也许是解锁我们想要的一件事的东西，
stateless, okay?
无状态，好吗？
Now, that's one piece. So what I want to look at is some of these other pieces that we're looking to unlock and some of the things that we're trying to get rid of.
现在，那是一件。因此，我想看的是我们想要解锁的其他一些作品，以及我们试图摆脱的一些东西。
So I'm going to erase some of this scribbly bits.
因此，我将删除其中一些杂乱无章的位。
Okay.
好的。
So, in Vitalik's picture, roadmap image, we end up looking at a number of things.
因此，在Vitalik的图片中，路线图的图像，我们最终看了许多事情。
So over time, we ended up with, or the initial design of Ethereum has a whole bunch of things that grow linearly over time.
因此，随着时间的流逝，我们结束了，或者以太坊的最初设计具有一大堆随着时间的线性生长的东西。
And while they are not necessarily, like, fundamentally going to, like, kill Ethereum or make Ethereum nodes just sort of, like, stop working, they have shown, like, we found that they are kind of problematic in our protocol design because they give us these things that just keep growing.
尽管它们不一定是从根本上杀死以太坊或使以太坊节点只是停止工作，但他们已经表明，我们发现它们在我们的协议设计中有点问题，因为它们是有问题的给我们这些只是不断成长的东西。
So the simple one is just the blocks, right?
因此，简单的只是块，对吗？
over a very long period of time, we end up with, what is it, 19 million blocks, roughly,
在很长一段时间内，我们最终得到了什么，这是什么，大约有1900万个街区
around this number today. So there's this long, long history of 19 million blocks of things.
今天大约这个数字。因此，有1900万块事物的悠久历史。
And it turns out that, like, realistically, clients really only need the stuff that's,
事实证明，实际上，客户实际上只需要那些东西
like, right up here towards the front, and that everything else that's in the deep, deep, deep,
就像，在这里朝前部，以及深，深，深，深，深，
deep history is mostly not that important for everyday operation of the protocol.
深层历史对于协议的日常运作并不重要。
In fact, with the advent of the beacon chain, the deep, long history is not even something that you
实际上，随着信标链的出现，深厚的历史甚至不是你
can actually reasonably follow because of this whole beacon chain subjectivity piece, where you
实际上，由于整个信标连锁主观性作品，您可以合理地遵循
actually need to jump to the front of the chain so um in order to track things so one of the things
实际上需要跳到链的前部，所以要跟踪事物，所以其中之一
that is being worked on and it's sort of like probably front of mind and one of the simplest
这是正在努力的，它可能像是头脑的前面，也是最简单的
ones is what we call four fours and good job to light client for sniping a eip number it's
我们称之为四个四分之一的好工作，可以点亮客户端以抢夺eip号码
really easy to remember here uh so four fours is one of our eips um and the proposal is that
在这里真的很容易记住，所以四个四分之一是我们的eips之一，建议是
clients start dropping their deep history, that clients start getting rid of the deep history
客户开始放弃他们的深刻历史，客户开始摆脱深刻的历史
of all of the headers and the blocks and everything like that. Now it turns out that that
在所有标题和块中，以及这样的一切。现在事实证明
has been quite a difficult thing for us to figure out how to do, because where is that data going to
对于我们来说，弄清楚该怎么做是一件艰难的事情，因为这些数据在哪里
come from, how are clients going to sync to the front of the chain, right, what if we lose this
来自，客户如何同步到链的前部，对，如果我们输了
data is one of the things that people like to say um i actually think what if we lose the data is
数据是人们喜欢说嗯的事情之一，我实际上认为如果我们丢失数据是什么
probably the least interesting one here because the it is my belief that the chance of us losing
可能是最不有趣的人，因为我相信我们失去的机会
the history of ethereum is near zero there's just too many people doing things with this with this
以太坊的历史接近零，有太多的人因此而做事
piece of technology for us to lose it but it is important to say like where are people going to
我们要丢失它的技术，但重要的是要说像人们要去哪里
to be able to get it reliably, that sort of thing.
能够可靠地获得这种事情。
So 4-4s is one of the tech debt cleanups
因此4-4S是技术债务清理之一
that we're working on doing,
我们正在努力做
which is to say that clients themselves
这就是说客户自己
do not need to keep that deep history.
不需要保持这么深刻的历史。
We'll get into kind of like how some of this works later,
我们会像以后的某些工作一样进入某种程度上，
but I believe that there are kind of
但是我相信有一些
like three approaches going on here.
就像这里发生的三种方法一样。
I think Aragon is looking at a torrent-based solution.
我认为Aragon正在研究基于洪流的解决方案。
So Aragon likes to do things kind of their own way.
因此，阿拉贡喜欢做自己的方式。
And Aragon, at least, I didn't double check all of this immediately before this talk, but at least in history,
至少Aragon，我没有在这次演讲之前立即仔细检查所有这些，但至少在历史上，
they've been looking at using BitTorrent protocol in order to figure out how to sync these things.
他们一直在考虑使用Bittorrent协议来弄清楚如何同步这些内容。
There is another solution called ARA1 files, which are this kind of like flat file format.
还有另一个称为ARA1文件的解决方案，它像平面文件格式一样。
And these two things are very compatible with each other.
这两件事彼此非常兼容。
I don't know exactly what format Aragorn is using in their torrents, but I wouldn't be surprised if it was something like error files.
我不知道Aragorn在他们的洪流中使用了哪种格式，但是如果它像错误文件，我不会感到惊讶。
So error1 files are just a file format for clients to be able to at least ingest old deep block data, and it's kind of just an archive format for us to do.
因此，error1文件只是客户端至少能够摄入旧深块数据的文件格式，这只是我们要做的档案格式。
They have some nice properties to them, which are basically just the ability to do random access into them to be able to read directly in and get whichever block you want.
它们具有一些不错的特性，这些属性基本上只是可​​以随机访问它们的能力，以便能够直接读取并获得所需的任何封锁。
And then Portal is kind of the live, distributed, on-demand solution that I've been pioneering and building.
然后，门户是我一直在开创和建造的现场直播，按需解决方案。
It's very much my baby. It's my project. There's a lot of other people who work on it. I do not get all the credit for this.
这是我的孩子。这是我的项目。还有很多其他人在研究它。我没有为此获得所有的荣誉。
But Portal is a peer-to-peer decentralized network and protocol for storage and retrieval of Ethereum data.
但是门户网站是一种用于以太坊数据的存储和检索的对等分散的网络和协议。
And so history is the first data set that we've gone after. In the last few weeks, we've actually squashed the appropriate bugs that we needed to squash to actually get things really working. And we are basically starting to aggressively approach the ecosystem and say, hey, we are ready for you guys to pull this history data from us.
因此，历史是我们追溯到的第一个数据集。在过去的几周中，我们实际上已经挤压了我们需要挤压的适当错误，以使事情真正有效。我们基本上开始积极地接近生态系统，并说，嘿，我们已经准备好让你们从我们那里获取这些历史数据。
So, four-fours is just one of these things in the purge that we want to do, which is purging all of that old history data out of things.
因此，四四个只是我们要做的清除中的一件事情，它正在清除所有旧的历史数据。
And forgive me if I'm going to work my way through a couple of things that we're working on getting out of the protocol.
如果我要努力摆脱协议，请原谅我。
I didn't work too hard to try to construct a nice little clean narrative where we walk through these things.
我并没有太努力地尝试构建一个很好的干净叙述，我们可以在这些过程中浏览这些东西。
um they're they're all very much attached to kind of like the core protocol pieces but they are a
嗯，他们都非常依恋，就像核心协议件一样，但它们是一个
little bit all over the place in terms of what things we're doing um another one of the things
在我们正在做的事情方面，一点点遍布另一件事
that we are working on getting out of the protocol is this op code called self-destruct
我们正在努力摆脱协议的是此称为自我毁灭的OP代码
um so self-destruct in its current and historical form uh clears the storage data for a contract
嗯，当前和历史形式的自我毁灭都清除了合同的存储数据
um originally it seemed like a pretty good idea to have this concept of a contract being able to
嗯，最初有这个合同能够能够的概念似乎是一个很好的主意
decide to delete itself. Um, and when we look at, so when we look at things like the state tree
决定删除自己。嗯，当我们看时，当我们看状态树之类的东西时
and it's got right, all of these things hanging off of it, and then you get to a contract
而且它是正确的，所有这些事情都将其悬挂在一起，然后您签订了合同
and then the contract down here has a few things in it that are, you know, stored under it.
然后，这里的合同中有几件事，您知道在其中存储了几件事。
The idea is that when this contract decides to self-destruct, all of this is supposed to go away.
这个想法是，当该合同决定自我毁灭时，所有这些都应该消失。
Well, that's fine and all, in kind of some of the original designs for how Ethereum is designed.
好吧，这很好，所有这些都是针对以太坊设计的一些原始设计。
And to understand that, we look at how the State Tree is designed.
为了理解这一点，我们研究了状态树的设计。
So the State Tree has all of these, it's got this whole tree branching structure, and you get down here, and it doesn't actually look like this.
因此，状态树拥有所有这些，它具有整个树的分支结构，您可以在这里到达，实际上并不是这样。
The state tree really just has an account down here and a state root for the account storage along with a couple of other fields like a knots and a balance and things like that.
状态树确实在这里只有一个帐户，并且是帐户存储的状态根，以及其他几个领域，例如结，平衡等。
It turns out that this is the only thing in the state tree that represents the storage for the contract.
事实证明，这是代表合同存储的状态树中唯一的东西。
Now, that contract storage has to live somewhere, right? And it has all of this data hanging down under it. But this is not inside of this. It does not live inside of this state tree. It has only got this reference.
现在，该合同存储必须居住在某个地方，对吗？它的所有这些数据都挂在其下面。但这不是其中的。它不在这条状态树内。它只有此参考。
And when you go and implement the Ethereum protocol and the MPG as it exists today, what you realize is that there's a couple of these things.
当您去实施以太坊协议和今天存在的MPG时，您会意识到有几个事情。
So there's this other one right here called the code hash, right?
因此，这里有另一个称为代码哈希，对吗？
The contract itself, the account, has this big, you know, some of them have like large, large code streams to them.
您知道，合同本身，帐户很大，其中一些人喜欢大型的大型代码流。
That code is not actually stored anywhere in the state tree.
该代码实际上并未存储在状态树中。
it is only referenced opaquely from this code hash,
仅从此代码哈希（Hash）中引用它，
similar to how the state root is only referenced opaquely
类似于状态根的方式仅不透明引用
through this hash right here.
在这里通过这个哈希。
At the implementation level,
在实施级别，
we actually have to store the code somewhere
实际上，我们必须将代码存储在某个地方
because when we go to execute the code at an account,
因为当我们在帐户中执行代码时，
the EVM needs that code to read it,
EVM需要该代码阅读，
which means that the client implementation
这意味着客户实施
has to store it somewhere.
必须将其存储在某个地方。
But it isn't in any of these places it is only referenced and so and so the client has to actually store it somewhere. This is where we actually get a little bit of like storage leak inside of clients.
但这并不是在这些地方都被引用的任何地方，因此客户必须将其实际存储在某个地方。在这里，我们实际上会得到客户内部的存储泄漏。
um two so a client has to decide in its implementation am i going to deduplicate
嗯两个，所以客户必须决定其实施，我将重复说明
contract code or am i going to do reference counting or am i going to just leak uh uh
合同代码或我要进行参考计数，还是我要泄露嗯，呃
contract codes and so those three things may not i'll try to describe them all so you have to store
合同代码，因此这三件事可能不会尝试所有这些内容，以便您必须存储
this code somewhere. So the naive implementation is every time I receive, I encounter new contract
此代码在某个地方。因此，每次我收到新合同
code, then I will store it in my key value database under this code hash. What that means
代码，然后我将其存储在此代码哈希下的密钥值数据库中。这意味着什么
is that if two contracts deploy the same code, I'm going to have one entry in my database for
是，如果两个合同部署相同的代码，我将在数据库中有一个条目
that code, while there are multiple accounts out here that have the same code hash. That means that
该代码，虽然这里有多个帐户具有相同的代码哈希。这意味着
when this account self-destructs, I can clear its data, but I can't actually clear its code out of
当这个帐户自我毁灭时，我可以清除其数据，但是我实际上无法清除其代码
my database because I don't know if there is another account down here that stores the same
我的数据库是因为我不知道这里是否有另一个帐户存储相同的帐户
code. And if I go delete it, and then this other one goes to execute, then I'm kind of screwed.
代码。如果我删除它，然后另一个执行，那我就被搞砸了。
So the typical implementation is this. They store it, and then they never delete it, which means
因此，典型的实现是这样。他们存储它，然后从未删除它，这意味着
that a long-running Ethereum client
那个长期运行的以太坊客户
is actually kind of accumulating extra code
实际上是积累额外的代码
that it shouldn't be holding onto
它不应该坚持
because of this whole implementation.
由于整个实施。
Now, you can do some overhead
现在，你可以做一些开销
to either do reference counting.
要么进行参考计数。
I forgot the other thing that I said,
我忘记了我说的另一件事，
but either way, you can do some overhead
但是无论哪种方式，您都可以做一些开销
to do better cleanup or better deletion,
为了更好地清理或更好的删除，
or you can store extra
或者您可以存储额外的
and store copies of all of it for each account
并为每个帐户存储所有副本
so that you know that you can just delete
这样你就知道你可以删除
that account's copy.
该帐户的副本。
But either way, you're talking about overhead,
但是无论哪种方式，您都在谈论开销，
terms of storage. This is another place where we cleaned something up with
存储条款。这是我们清理某些东西的另一个地方
Vercl. So Vercl actually stores the code itself inside of the main state tree. So
VERCL。因此，VERCL实际上将代码本身存储在主状态树中。所以
these are some of the places where we needed to do cleanup. This is another one
这些是我们需要进行清理的地方。这是另一个
of those places where providing proofs was complicated or is complicated in
在提供证据复杂或复杂的地方
the Merkle Patricia Tree model of things. If you imagine trying to provide the
事物的默克尔·帕特里夏树模型。如果您想象试图提供
naive implementation of providing a Merkle Patricia tree proof for execution
幼稚地实施提供默克尔帕特里夏树以进行执行
of a block you might forget that you that you need to include the actual code
在一个块中，您可能会忘记您需要包含实际代码
for any code that is encountered within within the execution of a block because
对于在块执行中遇到的任何代码，因为
the Merkle Patricia tree again it only has a reference to the code hash not the
默克尔·帕特里夏（Merkle Patricia）再次仅参考代码哈希而不是代码
code itself so getting back to self-destruct we've got this reference
代码本身，因此回到自我毁灭，我们有此参考
to a state root, the contract state is not actually stored anywhere inside of
在状态根目的上，合同状态实际上并未存储在内部的任何地方
the actual state tree. Client implementations have to just implement a
实际状态树。客户实现只需实施一个
thing to store it elsewhere, it's just to store that state somewhere else, and thus
将其存储在其他地方的东西，只是将该状态存储在其他地方，从而将
when a self-destruct comes through in this model, in the old Merkle-Patricia
当这种模型中有自我毁灭时，
tree model, a client can go through and actually delete every single one of these out of their
树模型，客户可以通过并实际删除其中的每一个。
database. But the thing is that a contract might have one, two, or a hundred billion
数据库。但是事实是合同可能有一个，二或一亿
state entries in its database. And when you run into that hundred billion model,
其数据库中的状态条目。当您遇到那亿款模型时，
and you implement your client so that it walks through this tree and deletes every one of these
然后您实现客户，以便它穿过这棵树并删除其中的每一个
keys out of your database, all of a sudden your client hangs while executing a block because it
钥匙从数据库中出来，您的客户在执行块时突然挂起，因为它
spends a couple of hours digging through its database, deleting all of this stuff.
花几个小时在其数据库中挖掘，删除所有这些内容。
And that is not an okay design. In the old Merkle partition tree, we can kind of get around this by
这不是一个可以的设计。在旧的默克尔分区树中，我们可以通过
just sort of like nuking this reference and just leaving this stuff around if we want to.
就像毫无意义的参考资料一样，如果我们愿意的话，就把这些东西留在周围。
The problem is that we fixed this in the Virkle.
问题在于我们将其修复在virkle中。
So Virkle is one of the places where we cleaned a lot of stuff up.
因此，Virkle是我们清理了很多东西的地方之一。
And in Virkle, this stuff, the contract storage stuff, does not live separate.
在virkle中，这些东西，合同存储的东西并不分开。
It does not live in this kind of magic-made-up other area.
它不生活在这种神奇的其他领域。
It is inside of the main state tree.
它位于主状态树的内部。
In fact, everything is inside of the main state tree.
实际上，一切都在主要状态树的内部。
This is one of the really nice cleanups that Virkle did.
这是Virkle所做的非常漂亮的清理工作之一。
But in doing so, in doing this, it means that self-destruct becomes incredibly problematic, because if we're going to allow self-destructs, and we have the data inside of the main tree, it means that we're sort of required to go through and delete all of those things, which means that we introduce sort of a denial-of-service factor with self-destructs.
但是这样做，这样做，这意味着自我毁灭会变得难以置信的问题，因为如果我们要允许自我毁灭，并且我们的数据在主树的内部，则意味着我们有点需要经历并删除所有这些内容，这意味着我们引入了一种自我毁灭的拒绝服务因素。
So self-destruct removal, self-destruct essentially,
因此，自我毁灭的去除，本质上是自我毁灭的，
like in order to do this transition,
像为了进行这种过渡一样
we have to deal with self-destruct.
我们必须处理自我毁灭。
So self-destruct, one of the things
如此自我毁灭，其中之一
that we get rid of in the purge.
我们摆脱了清除。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
All right.
好的。
So precompiles are another one of the things that are being looked at for wanting to do purge things.
因此，预编译是要清除事情的另一件事。
So I think we've all heard of something like zkevm, zero-knowledge evm stuff.
因此，我认为我们都听说过ZKEVM，零知识EVM的东西。
any sort of this category of technology applied to EVM execution.
任何类型的技术都应用于EVM执行。
So one of the problems that shows up in being able to zero-knowledge-ify zk-evm things are precompiles.
因此，出现的问题之一是能够零知识 -  ZK-EVM事物是预编译。
Kekak is one of the other ones.
Kekak是其他人之一。
So it turns out that precompiles and Kekak being one of those are really kind of fundamentally problematic for doing zk things.
因此，事实证明，预编译和Kekak是其中之一，实际上是有问题的ZK事情。
Now, I'm going to do a lot of hand-waving in this part, because this is not my domain of deep expertise. I understand these things at a high level. I do not have deep knowledge of the fundamentals of how they work.
现在，我将在这部分中进行大量努力，因为这不是我深厚的专业知识的领域。我高度了解这些事情。我对它们的工作方式没有深入的了解。
But what I do understand is that implementing KECAC in this model accounts for a very large percentage of the computation that must be done in order to z-k-fi things, in order to zero-knowledge-fi things.
但是我确实了解的是，在此模型中实施KECAC是为了使Z-K-Fi事情要做Zero-newledge-Fi的事物，必须完成的计算中很大一部分的计算。
And so we had this idea in the origin, you know, kind of the origin, the inception of Ethereum, that we wanted things like Kekak, because our protocol itself, right, Ethereum's protocol has Kekak all over the place.
因此，我们知道，我们在来源中有了这个想法，即以太坊的成立，是我们想要Kekak之类的东西，因为我们的协议本身，对以太坊的协议在各地都有kekak。
This is how we acquire block caches. Kekak is all over the Merkle Patricia tree, right?
这就是我们获得块缓存的方式。凯卡克（Kekak）遍布梅克尔·帕特里夏（Merkle Patricia）树，对吗？
And so having Kekak available inside of the EVM was really valuable.
因此，在EVM内部使用Kekak确实很有价值。
same with things like SHA-256
与SHA-256这样的东西也一样
SHA-256 is used to secure
SHA-256用于固定
all kinds of data all over the place
到处都是各种数据
and being able to do
并能够做
SHA-256 cheap in the EVM
EVM中的SHA-256便宜
was valuable
很有价值
so there's a lot of use cases
所以有很多用例
around that but what it turns
在那周围，它变成了
out is that by including
是通过包括
these kinds of things what we do
这类事情我们要做的事情
is we make doing zk things
我们是做ZK的事情吗
fundamentally hard
从根本上硬
that
那
that applying zk things to these makes them fundamentally hard and so one of the areas
将ZK的事物应用于这些方面使它们从根本上困难，因此是其中之一
of cleanup that we are looking to that people are working on is essentially
我们正在寻找人们正在进行的清理工作本质上是
evmifying to the best that we can pre-compiles and trying to figure out what we do with the
尽力而为，我们可以预先编译并试图弄清楚我们对
rest of them so one of the things that is standing in the way of this are all of these
其余的
types of things of precompiles. So this is why we are trying to kind of like find ways to get these
预编译的事物类型。所以这就是为什么我们试图找到获取这些的方法
out. One of the major efforts where this stuff is happening is the Ethereum object format. I believe
出去。这些事情发生的主要工作之一是以太坊对象格式。我相信
that there's links to this stuff in the protocol studies documents related to this talk. But
协议研究文档中与此演讲有关的文档中有指向这些内容的链接。但
Ethereum object format is one of the places where large amounts of this kind of cleanup are happening.
以太坊对象格式是发生大量此类清理的地方之一。
So, the reason for getting, you know, wanting to get rid of pre-compiles is wanting to get rid of, well, not get rid of, but make it possible for us to get to this kind of zk-evm place.
因此，您知道要摆脱预编译的原因是要摆脱前，不要摆脱，而是让我们有可能进入这种ZK-EVM的位置。
Because as amazing as a vertical is with the ability for us to distribute
因为像垂直行业一样惊人，是我们分发的能力
vertical proofs of the states that make black execution
使黑色执行的状态的垂直证明
Easy to do
容易做
at the client level because all you have to do is
在客户层面，因为您要做的就是
Have the block be you want to execute and the proof and you can run it all in memory and you don't have to
让您要执行和证明的块，您可以将其全部运行在内存中，而您不必
Store any state and that sort of thing it's great as great as that is
存储任何状态和类似的东西，它很棒
What's even greater is the world here?
这里的世界更大？
where at that point, the proofs get even smaller
到那时，证据变得更小
and the verification of the proofs get even faster.
证明的验证甚至更快。
Because it turns out that even in a Virkle model,
因为事实证明即使在virkle模型中，
executing a block is relatively CPU expensive
执行一个块相对昂贵
and in kind of like a light client world,
就像一个轻度的客户世界一样，
doing that on things like mobile phones
在手机之类的事情上做到这一点
is still probably more expensive than we want it to be.
可能仍然比我们想要的要贵。
Whereas this in theory is actually accessible
从理论上讲，这实际上是可以访问的
in the kind of like resource-constrained light device world.
以类似资源受限的轻型设备世界。
This feels like an appropriate spot to pause.
这是一个合适的停顿地点。
I really probably should have paused and seen if there's any questions
我真的应该暂停并看到是否有任何疑问
at at least one of the previous topic boundaries.
至少以前的主题边界之一。
But do we have any questions or anything that people want me to dig into?
但是，我们有任何问题或任何人希望我深入研究的问题吗？
Any areas of clarification?
有澄清的领域吗？
Yeah, we have some questions on Discord.
是的，我们对不和谐有一些疑问。
First, is it difficult because precompiles are not defined to EVM's language code, or
首先，很难，因为未定义为EVM的语言代码或
zkvm in the context that you said a moment ago?
ZKVM在您刚才说的上下文中？
Yes.
是的。
So precompiles are not EVM code, typically.
因此，通常通常不是EVM代码。
They tend to be machine code.
它们倾向于是机器代码。
Or just external, right?
还是外部，对吗？
Like, I don't know what the other clients have done.
就像，我不知道其他客户做了什么。
I decided to write a client many years ago in Python.
我决定多年前在Python写一位客户。
It was a mistake, but I learned so much doing it,
这是一个错误，但是我学到了很多事情，
so maybe it wasn't a mistake.
所以也许这不是一个错误。
But either way, in my Python clients,
但是无论哪种方式，在我的Python客户中，
when you called the precompile that did Kekak,
当您打电话给kekak的预编译时，
I used the Python library that does Kekak,
我使用了kekak的python库
and I feed it through, and I do Kekak,
我喂了它，我做了凯卡克，
and I hope that the Python library does exactly the right thing.
我希望Python图书馆做得完全正确。
In fact, I think that a lot of the bugs that people find in fuzzers tend to be in kind of like the precompile area, because you're going to get slightly different behaviors with things like number overflows and stuff in a go library, maybe than an arrest library than in a C library that was written differently.
实际上，我认为人们在模糊器中发现的许多错误往往像预编译区域一样，因为您将在GO库中获得诸如数字溢出和内容之类的行为，也许是比逮捕图书馆比在c图书馆中撰写的图书馆不同。
And so most of the clients are essentially shelling out to some other library that implements SHA-256, KECAC, whatever it is, Blake2B, those things.
因此，大多数客户本质上都在向其他一些实现SHA-256，KECAC的库，无论是Blake2b，这些东西。
So yeah, I don't know what the state of the art is for what the plan for how we do KECAC going forward, or if we do, or how we do SHA-256 going forward, or if we do.
所以，是的，我不知道我们对KECAC未来的计划的计划是什么，或者我们是否这样做，或者我们如何做SHA-256，或者如果我们这样做。
I don't know if it becomes viable for us to do those things at the EVM level.
我不知道我们能在EVM级别上做这些事情是否可行。
But either way, the problem is that they shell out to machine code,
但是无论哪种方式，问题在于他们将机器代码淘汰，
which means that how do you do a zk-proof for something that is just a go library being run on your machine?
这意味着您如何为仅在计算机上运行的GO库做一个ZK-POND-PRODACE？
I think that's kind of where the problem comes up.
我认为这是问题出现的地方。
Great, thank you so much.
太好了，非常感谢。
Yeah, the brick compiles are quite complex topic, and we also have an article on that on the APF
是的，砖头编译是非常复杂的话题，我们在APF上也有一篇文章
Wikipedia, it's also put there. And I have another question, because I didn't quite catch that,
维基百科，也放在那里。我还有另一个问题，因为我还没有抓住那个，
when you were mentioning, we were explaining the self-destruct mechanism and how the contract code
当您提到时，我们正在解释自我毁灭机制以及合同代码
is stored, you mentioned that there is some storage leakage or some sort of leak happening,
存储，您提到有一些存储泄漏或某种泄漏正在发生，
and uh i didn't really catch that can you elaborate from that like what is the what is
嗯，我并没有真正抓住你能从那是什么样子中详细说明
illegal got it um so you can you can look at this in either contract code bridge and both i believe
非法掌握了，所以您可以在任何合同代码桥上查看它，我都相信
actually end up having the same mechanism so because the existing state of how the merkle
实际上最终具有相同的机制，因此，因为现有的状态
patriciatory stores the ethereum state only has references via code hash or or the contract
以太坊状态仅通过代码哈希或或合同具有参考文献
storage route, a client who's doing either a self-destruct, who's doing a self-destruct
存储路线，正在做自我毁灭的客户，正在做自我毁灭的客户
has to decide whether or not they're going to delete the code itself and whether or not
必须决定是否要删除代码本身以及是否
they're going to delete the storage elements themselves.
他们将自己删除存储元素。
The hygienic thing to do is, in theory, to delete them.
从理论上讲，要做的卫生要做的事情是删除它们。
But to implement that naively means possibly allowing your client to get DOST off the network.
但是，实现这一目标意味着可能允许您的客户从网络上脱离网络。
So in the event that a very large contract deletes itself, there might be hundreds of thousands or millions of storage keys that need to be deleted.
因此，如果一份非常大的合同本身会删除，则可能需要删除数十万或数百万的存储键。
And if you naively implement self-destruct so that it actually goes through and delete those, what you might find is that during a block that calls self-destruct on a very large contract, that your client is going to hang for a very long time trying to do that deletion.
而且，如果您天真地实施自我毁灭，以便实际上经过并删除这些毁灭，那么您可能会发现，在一个称为大型合同上的自我毁灭的街区中，您的客户将悬挂很长时间试图做到这一点。
Which means that you probably need to put some limits on how long your client is going to spend deleting them.
这意味着您可能需要限制客户将花费多长时间删除它们。
If you want to be really hygienic, but realistically, I think the reality is that the smart thing to do if you want to write a client that is robust, it's just not to delete that stuff or to put some really strict limits on how many keys you're willing to spend time deleting before you force your client to move on.
如果您想真正卫生，但实际上，我认为现实是，如果您想编写一个强大的客户，那要做的事情是，这只是不是要删除这些东西或对多少限制了多少钥匙您愿意花时间删除，然后再迫使客户继续前进。
and then potentially to never ever come back and clean that stuff up.
然后有可能再也不会回来清理这些东西了。
So for contract storage, you get that DOS vector where it's maybe difficult to clean up a contract
因此，对于合同存储，您会得到DOS矢量，可能很难清理合同
that self-destructs itself that has a very, very large amount of storage keys.
这种自我毁灭本身具有非常大量的存​​储键。
So there you get a kind of like storage leakage where your database will use store contract storage
因此，您会得到某种像存储泄漏，您的数据库将使用商店合同存储
over some period of time if you don't implement perfect deletion mechanics,
在一段时间内，如果您不实施完美的删除机制，
which are not it's not infeasible to do that engineering work but it isn't the most important
做工程工作不是不可行的，但不是最重要的
thing i think that most clients work on so it's not unreasonable to expect that many clients or
我认为大多数客户都在工作的事情，因此期望许多客户或
some clients or maybe even all clients um i don't know what they do under the hood but i wouldn't
有些客户，甚至所有客户，我都不知道他们在引擎盖下做什么，但我不会
be surprised if there are clients out there that when a self-destruct happens they don't actually
如果有客户，当发生自我毁灭时，他们实际上并没有感到惊讶
wipe everything off disk which means that over a long-running uh ethereum client that stays online
从磁盘上擦除所有内容
and it doesn't reset it's it's storage databases and things will accumulate
它并没有重置它的存储数据库，而事物会累积
cruft in its database extra storage in this database that should it is
在此数据库中的数据库中的额外存储在该数据库中
deletable but yes but it wasn't deleted because maybe they made the smart choice
可删除但是的，但没有删除，因为也许他们做出了明智的选择
to to put limits or even just to say you know what we're not even gonna clean up
要限制限制，甚至只是说您知道我们甚至都不会清理
contract storage deletions we're just gonna let it sit so that we don't get
合同存储删除我们只会让它坐下来，以免我们得到
dosed off the network because this isn't the highest priority issue that we have
从网络中加入，因为这不是我们遇到的最高优先级问题
to work on right now.
现在就开始工作。
So that's where that stuff shows up with contract storage.
这就是这些东西带有合同存储的地方。
With contract code, it's much,
有了合同代码，
two contracts can share the exact same code,
两个合同可以共享完全相同的代码，
which means they'll have the exact same code hash,
这意味着他们将具有完全相同的代码哈希，
which means that at the implementation level,
这意味着在实施级别，
since the code is not stored in the state tree,
由于代码未存储在状态树中，因此
the client has a choice about how they store it,
客户可以选择如何存储它，
and the naive way to store it is to store it by its hash.
存储它的天真方法是通过哈希储存。
And since two accounts can have the exact same code hash
而且由于两个帐户可以具有完全相同的代码哈希
and can have identical code,
并且可以具有相同的代码，
if you choose that mechanism,
如果您选择该机制，
when a contract self-destructs,
当合同自我毁灭时，
you can't go delete its code from your database
您不能从数据库中删除其代码
because you don't know whether or not
因为你不知道是否
there is another account that has the same code.
还有另一个具有相同代码的帐户。
That's where that leakage happens.
那就是泄漏发生的地方。
These are not major, major issues.
这些不是主要问题。
These are not issues that are going to, like,
这些不是会遇到的问题
immediately cause a client to fall off the network or anything like that, they are just
立即导致客户脱离网络或类似的东西，它们只是
little bits of debt that over time cause clients to store more data than they're required to.
随着时间的流逝，很少的债务会导致客户存储比他们需要更多的数据。
And they're probably not the highest engineering problems that most client teams,
而且它们可能不是大多数客户团队的最高工程问题，
they're probably not the highest priority engineering problems that most client teams work
他们可能不是大多数客户团队工作的最高优先工程问题
on. All right, thank you so much. That's very interesting. I didn't know about the
在。好的，非常感谢。那很有趣。我不知道
a potential dose vector there that's pretty interesting.
那里的潜在剂量向量非常有趣。
The next question is on portal report,
下一个问题是在门户网站报告中
and I think you can just go on
我想你可以继续
and we'll get to this topic eventually.
最终我们将获得这个话题。
Yeah, I think we've got two,
是的，我想我们有两个，
like two and a half more kind of purge topics,
像两个半的清除话题一样，
and then I'll pause for a second,
然后我会暂停一秒钟，
and then we'll do a bit of kind of like what is portal
然后我们会做一些类似的门户
and where are we going with it?
我们要去哪里？
So one of the other major areas of cleanup
因此，清理的其他主要领域之一
that we want to do is in the state, right?
我们想做的是在州，对吗？
Earlier, we talked about how 4-4s is aiming at cleaning up
早些时候，我们谈到了4-4S的目的是如何清理
this long history of linear growth, right?
线性增长的悠久历史，对吗？
This very long history of blocks, and it grows over time.
这一悠久的块历史随着时间的流逝而增长。
The state itself has this very long history
国家本身拥有如此悠久的历史
of linear growth, right?
线性增长，对吗？
The state tree just keeps getting bigger and bigger
状态树不断越来越大
and bigger and bigger, and we just keep throwing more
而且越来越大，我们只是继续投掷更多
and more stuff, and we need it all to be there.
还有更多的东西，我们需要所有这些东西才能在那里。
So what are we gonna do about that?
那我们该怎么办？
How do we clean it up?
我们如何清理它？
And years ago, when we came together to try to kind of fix these problems, we came up with this concept that we call state expiry.
几年前，当我们聚集在一起试图解决这些问题时，我们提出了这个称为州到期的概念。
Which actually is probably a terrible name because it makes it it's it's it's the expiry is like a violent word, right?
实际上，哪个可能是一个可怕的名字，因为它使它成为一个暴力词，对吗？
It says it expires. It goes away. Right.
它说它到期了。它消失了。正确的。
So maybe we should we should talk about some branding at some point and come up with a with a with a nicer, friendlier word here.
因此，也许我们应该在某个时候谈论一些品牌，并在这里提出一个带有更好，更友好的词的品牌。
But today we're going to call it state expiry because that's what we've called it in protocol discussions for forever.
但是今天，我们将其称为状态到期，因为这就是我们永远在协议讨论中所说的。
And maybe we'd get less fear if we used a different word than expiry.
如果我们使用的词与到期不同的话，也许我们会减少恐惧。
Because the truth is that it doesn't actually expire. It just kind of goes to sleep. That's the idea.
因为事实是它实际上没有过期。只是睡觉。那就是主意。
So the idea is that we define epics, right? We got epics all over the place, right?
因此，我们的想法是我们定义史诗，对吗？我们到处都是史诗，对吗？
it's this whole thing. And the idea behind state expiry is, and I'm only going to hit this at the
这是整个事情。国家到期背后的想法是，我只会在
highest level, because there's a lot of nuance here. The idea behind state expiry is this, is that
最高水平，因为这里有很多细微差别。国家到期背后的想法是
for now, we'll say this is today. Today, we are inside this epic, okay? There's a bunch of these
现在，我们会说这是今天。今天，我们在这个史诗般的内部，好吗？有很多
hanging out back here too.
也在这里闲逛。
So under this epic,
因此，在这个史诗般的情况下
we have a state.
我们有一个状态。
And so do we have a state
我们也有一个状态
under every single one
每个人
of these other epics as well.
这些其他史诗也是如此。
And this one hasn't happened yet.
而且这还没有发生。
Okay?
好的？
And during a block that's executed
在执行的块中
in this epic right here,
在这个史诗般的就在这里，
when it reads state,
当它读取状态时
first it will try
首先会尝试
to read from this one.
从此阅读。
it will see if the value is there or not. And when it writes state it will always write
它将查看该值是否存在。当它写成状态时，它将永远写
to this one. So this one, we read from it, and we write from it. In the event that state
对此。因此，我们从中读出来，然后从中读书。如果该状态
is missing from this one, the idea is that we reach back into this kind of like previous
这是缺少的，这个想法是我们像以前一样回到这种情况
tree of the state. Let me try to read the state from back here. And if it's not in either of
国家树。让我尝试从这里阅读状态。如果不是
these, then too bad it's not here. If it is here, what we do is we elevate it into the active state.
这些，太糟糕了，它不在这里。如果在这里，我们要做的就是将其提升到活动状态。
So we have this concept of kind of the active state and the previous state.
因此，我们有这种活跃状态和先前状态的概念。
And the idea is that these epics might be six months, nine months, 12 months long, something in this rough realm, and that every time you cross an epic boundary, you say, well, the previous state here is now read-only.
这个想法是，这些史诗可能是六个月，九个月，12个月的时间，这是一个粗糙的领域，并且每当您越过史诗般的边界时，您都会说，现在这里的先前状态现在只读。
Now we get a nice new empty one that is read-write, and anything that's getting regularly accessed within this time frame will just automatically move itself forward.
现在，我们得到了一个不错的新空名，它是读写的，并且在此时间范围内定期访问的任何东西都会自动向前移动。
And anything that doesn't still lives back here, but the clients no longer keep this one around.
而且任何仍然没有回到这里的东西，但客户不再将其保留在这里。
It still exists.
它仍然存在。
Somebody's got it.
有人明白了。
we probably make something like an error file format for it
我们可能会为其制作类似错误的文件格式
so that people can package it up really nicely,
这样人们就可以很好地打包
ship it around, make torrents for it, or anything like that.
将其运送到周围，为之制作洪流或类似的东西。
And then the mechanism here is that in the event
然后这里的机制是
that you're doing something here
你在这里做某事
that really needs to access something
确实需要访问某些东西
from back a couple of epics ago
从几个史诗般的后面开始
that is no longer immediately accessible in the EVM
在EVM中不再可以立即访问
because clients are allowed to drop things that are past this boundary,
因为允许客户放弃超越这个边界的东西，所以
the idea is that it is pretty easy for the Ethereum protocol
这个想法是，对于以太坊协议来说，它非常容易
to just keep track of the old routes.
只是跟踪旧路线。
And as long as the protocol keeps track of all of these old state routes,
只要协议跟踪所有这些旧状态路线，
then somebody can build themselves a proof
然后有人可以建立自己的证据
for a piece of state that they want to essentially revive,
对于他们想重新恢复的一种状态
and they can include it in their transaction
他们可以将其包括在交易中
so that when execution happens here
这样当执行在这里发生
that wants to access something back here
想在这里访问一些东西
that isn't immediately accessible,
这不是立即访问，
it can just look at this old root, check the proof,
它可以看一下这个旧的根，检查证明，
see that it matches the root,
看到它与根相匹配，
and then write it into the state.
然后将其写入状态。
So state expiry is this,
因此，国家有效期是这样，
really quite wonderful, nice, clean solution for this.
真的很棒，很好，干净的解决方案。
I think it's where we go.
我认为这是我们去的地方。
I think it's where we're going, but it's hard.
我认为这是我们要去的地方，但这很难。
It's a lot of work.
这是很多工作。
It's complex.
这很复杂。
The amount of, right, this is a big feature.
对，这是一个很大的功能。
This is a feature as big as Verkle, right?
这是一个像Verkle一样大的功能，对吗？
This is a fundamental change to kind of how Ethereum's protocol works.
这是以太坊协议如何工作的基本变化。
The expiry of old things is a new thing, right?
旧事物的到期是新事物，对吗？
But state expiry is one of these it's it's really the big purge item it is
但是国家到期就是其中之一，它确实是大清除物品
that can maybe the biggest thing in the purge that we want to do and it's hard
这可能是我们想做的最大的事情，这很难
but this is generally the concept. And I realize that this next topic that I want
但这通常是概念。我意识到我想要的下一个话题
to talk about, which is address space expansion, that I think I'm not going to be able to draw
谈论，这是解决空间扩展，我认为我将无法画画
you a perfect picture for why we need this.
您是我们为什么需要这个的完美图片。
But I will be able to give you what is generally a hand-wavy answer for this.
但是我将能够为您提供通常的手动答案。
And there are a lot of links in the protocol studies document that go into detail about
协议研究文档中有很多链接详细介绍
address space expansion and why we need it.
解决空间扩展以及为什么我们需要它。
But the general gist is that in each of these epics, we need a slightly different addressing scheme so that it's very clear which epic we're talking about.
但是，普遍的观点是，在这些史诗中，我们需要一个略有不同的寻址方案，以便非常清楚我们正在谈论哪种史诗。
And that addressing scheme, essentially, we don't have enough bits of entropy in our 20-byte Ethereum addresses.
从本质上讲，我们在20字节以太坊讲话中没有足够的熵。
I think the number that's been cited is that the Bitcoin blockchain has done this much computation, that the Bitcoin blockchain has effectively brute-forced at least a couple of Ethereum addresses in the amount of computation that has happened there.
我认为被引用的数字是，比特币区块链已经完成了这么多的计算，比特币区块链有效地遇到了蛮力至少在那里发生的计算量中的几个以太坊地址。
And so the analysis is that our 20-byte addresses are not actually secure enough for us to implement state expiry because they're just not big enough, right?
因此，分析是，我们的20个字节地址实际上还不够安全，无法实施国家到期，因为它们不够大，对吗？
We take a 32-byte value, and then we really truncate it down to a 20-byte value.
我们采用32字节值，然后将其截断为20字节值。
Um, and so while this is, you know, it's, it's complicated as well. State expiry is complicated, um, difficult to do. You know, it's, it's got a lot of moving parts. We, we, we really kind of know how to do all of this. This is like not, um, it's hard, but, but, but it's, it's, it's known in, in most ways.
嗯，虽然这是，但这也很复杂。州到期很复杂，很难做。您知道，它有很多活动部件。我们，我们，我们真的知道如何做所有这一切。嗯，这很难，但是，但是，它在大多数方面都以此为名。
What we ran into that was sort of the blocker was that this one actually was somewhat fundamentally hard, because there is a lot of stuff in our protocol that did very strict things about 20 byte addresses, like truncating values that were sent back and forth within the EVM, things like that.
我们所遇到的是阻碍者，这实际上是从根本上很难EVM，这样的事情。
And so, or even just the sheer amount of tooling out there that knows exactly how to do this and has no idea how to do 32-byte addresses.
因此，甚至只是大量的工具，这些工具完全知道如何做到这一点，并且不知道如何进行32字节的地址。
So address-based expansion ends up being actually one of the harder problems here, simply, I think, because this is a technical problem.
因此，基于地址的扩展最终实际上是这里更困难的问题之一，我认为这是一个技术问题。
State expiry is a technical problem.
州到期是一个技术问题。
Address-based expansion has a bit of technical problems buried in it, but it, boy, does have a lot of people problems.
基于地址的扩展存在一些埋藏的技术问题，但是它确实有很多人问题。
built in it, right? Lots and lots of client libraries that deal with 20-byte addresses,
内置，对吗？很多涉及20字节地址的客户库，
and it will blindly take a 32-byte address and just rip it down and turn it into a 20-byte
它将盲目地占据32字节的地址，然后将其撕下并将其变成20字节
address without saying anything about it or throwing any errors or anything like that.
地址，无话可说，也没有丢弃任何错误或类似的错误。
And so one of the blockers that we ran into was this thing right here with address space expansion.
因此，我们遇到的一个阻滞剂就是在这里扩展空间。
Um, cool. Um, any questions about this?
嗯，很酷。嗯，对此有任何疑问吗？
Uh, nothing specific to, to the state expiry stuff, unless people have some questions they
呃，没有什么具体的国家到期的东西，除非人们有一些问题
want to type in quickly. Uh, we have one coming that says, uh, in week five,
想快速输入。呃，我们有一个来了，嗯，在第五周，
Donathy mentioned that he believes state expiry might never get implemented due to complexity and that PBS and statelessness makes it a lower priority.
唐纳西（Donathy）提到，他认为由于复杂性，国家到期可能永远不会被实施，并且PBS和无状态使其成为较低的优先事项。
What are your thoughts on the likelihood that state expiry gets implemented?
您对国家到期实施的可能性有何看法？
I don't think I have an informed opinion here.
我认为我在这里没有明智的意见。
I have my own opinion, but I don't think I have an ecosystem-informed opinion.
我有自己的意见，但我认为我没有生态系统的意见。
I think that that stuff is correct, that there is a viable future in which we never implement state expiry.
我认为这是正确的，有一个可行的未来，我们永远不会实施国家到期。
I find that kind of disappointing, and I think I can lay out my reason for that.
我觉得那种令人失望的事情，我认为我可以理解我的理由。
it appears to be completely viable
它似乎是完全可行的
to never do state expiry
永远不要国家到期
that hardware should probably outpace state growth
该硬件可能应该超过状态增长
and that it is reasonable to expect block builders
并且可以期望阻止建造者是合理的
to throw high-end, great, amazing hardware at this stuff
在此东西上投掷高端，伟大，令人惊叹的硬件
and to be able to manage 10 terabyte state databases
并能够管理10个Terabyte状态数据库
and just to figure it out
只是为了弄清楚
and to do the engineering work to do that.
并做工程工作来做到这一点。
I think that is a viable future for what we do,
我认为这是我们所做工作的可行未来，
but boy, do I not like it.
但是男孩，我不喜欢它。
And some of this is directly influenced
其中一些人受到直接影响
by the context that I work in, which is portal network.
根据我工作的上下文，即门户网络。
And the reason is that the state
原因是国家
is a very hard data set to work with.
是一个非常困难的数据集。
you get this value that is the state root.
您将获得该值是状态根。
And the state root references this huge data set that lives under it.
国家根源参考了存在于其中的巨大数据集。
And not only references it, but the state changes fast, constantly, and kind of randomly.
不仅引用了它，而且国家随机变化迅速，不断变化。
And because of that, it's a very hard data set to work with
因此，这是一个非常困难的数据集合
because it's always trying to move out from under you.
因为它总是试图从您下方搬出。
If you have a copy of it, you've got to constantly be executing every single block that comes through.
如果您有副本，则必须不断执行每个块。
Otherwise, this thing that you worked so hard to gather and build and tend and love suddenly becomes borderline useless just because you were gone for 10 minutes.
否则，您努力地收集，建造和倾向和爱的事情突然变得无用，因为您已经走了10分钟。
And now you can't really do anything with it.
现在，您实际上无法做任何事情。
And that's not a great feeling.
这不是一个很好的感觉。
And we want – so in the PBS model, it's very protocol-focused, right?
我们想要 - 因此，在PBS模型中，它非常注重协议，对吗？
decision, I believe, to say, you know what? This is fine. This is okay. We're fine with,
我相信，可以说，你知道吗？这很好。没关系。我们很好，
it is totally viable for our protocol to just keep chugging on because block builders
我们的协议只能继续前进是完全可行的，因为块构建器
have a strong incentive to put big pieces of hardware at block building to store mega large
有强烈的动力将大型硬件放在街区建筑物上以存储大型大型
state trees and to have no problem at all doing block building and block execution.
陈述树，根本没有任何问题，进行块构建和阻止执行。
And I think this is sort of like a blinders view, because it's very protocol centric, which is not a bad way to do this development of the protocol. But what about users? This is kind of like my question.
我认为这有点像盲目的观点，因为它非常以协议为中心，这并不是完成协议发展的一种坏方法。但是用户呢？这有点像我的问题。
So, in order to build and send a transaction, I must do this thing that we do called gas
因此，为了建立和发送交易，我必须做我们称为煤气的事情
estimation.
估计。
And gas estimation means running arbitrary EVM code, and running arbitrary EVM code means
气体估计意味着运行任意EVM代码，并且运行任意EVM代码表示
accessing the state.
访问状态。
And so while the protocol can turn along just fine, how are users going to build transactions
因此，尽管协议可以很好地进行，但用户将如何构建交易
their own in a manner that is ideologically aligned with what we say we care about, which
他们自己的方式在意识形态上与我们所说的那样一致，
is decentralization and that sort of thing.
是权力下放，类似的事情。
Because a monolithic, giant, mega state means we are saying to users, you should go use
因为一个单片，巨大的大型状态意味着我们对用户说，所以您应该使用
centralized providers.
集中提供商。
You should go use Infura.
您应该使用infura。
You should go use Alchemy.
您应该去使用炼金术。
because that's what we're saying if we do that.
因为这就是我们要说的话。
State expiry puts bounds on the overall size of the state that is hard to work with.
州到期将很难与之合作的州的整体规模限制。
The state is still hard to work with in a state expiry model,
国家仍然很难在州到期模型中使用
but that difficulty is firmly bound into this box.
但是，这个困难被牢固地绑定到了这个盒子中。
And every time something expires out of here, it becomes very easy to work with
每当这里有某些东西到期时，与之合作变得非常容易
because it stops wiggling around
因为它停止摇摆
and moving out from under you
从你下方搬出
and it gets frozen.
它被冻结了。
And so it becomes viable
因此它变得可行
to build sustainable protocols
建立可持续协议
that can serve this state data.
可以提供此状态数据。
It is easier to build a portal network model
构建门户网络模型更容易
that serves this state data
为此状态数据服务
because there's upper bounds
因为有上限
on how much of it there ever will be.
关于其中的多少。
Whereas in the monolithic,
而在整体上，
single state, single route,
单状态，单路
no state expiry model,
没有州到期模型，
it means that a solution like portal network has to figure out how to continually grow its provided storage to be able to store all of this historical state in order to serve it.
这意味着像门户网络这样的解决方案必须弄清楚如何不断扩大其提供的存储空间，以便能够存储所有历史状态以服务。
So I'm sure that there's some holes in the reasoning there, but that's the rough gist of why I find that approach to be disappointing.
因此，我敢肯定，那里的推理中有一些漏洞，但这就是为什么我发现这种方法令人失望的原因。
Yeah, thank you so much for this paper.
是的，非常感谢您的论文。
I really appreciate it, because when Domotis said it, I was personally quite disappointed.
我真的很感激，因为当Domotis说出来时，我个人感到非常失望。
I was a fan of StateXparry exactly for the reasons you're saying.
由于您所说的原因，我完全是Statexparry的粉丝。
I'm learning a node, I'm learning an archive node, and I will keep doing this, providing
我正在学习一个节点，正在学习一个存档节点，我会继续这样做，提供
the data.
数据。
So it's great argumentation, Dave.
因此，这是一个很好的论点，戴夫。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
Yeah, we have one more question, because you mentioned address space extension, and it's
是的，我们还有一个问题，因为您提到了地址空间扩展，这是
something that I haven't heard about in a while now.
我已经有一段时间没有听说过的东西了。
I wonder what's the priority there?
我想知道那里的优先事项是什么？
What is the current research state of the ASE?
当前的ASE研究状态是什么？
I know that EOF, so Ethereum Object Format,
我知道EOF，因此以太坊对象格式，
is doing some of the work to make address-based expansion possible.
正在做一些工作以使基于地址的扩展成为可能。
So it seems to be prioritized.
因此，它似乎是优先的。
I haven't had my thumb on the pulse of core development for a bit.
我暂时没有拇指对核心开发的脉搏。
I've been very much off in my own portal project,
我在自己的门户网站项目中一直处于困境，
And so I've stayed, I've been catching up, but I don't know.
因此，我一直待在，我一直在赶上，但我不知道。
I can talk more generically about it, which is that most things in our ecosystem get done because of a few very motivated people who decide to die on that hill, who decide to take up the flag and run with it and make it happen.
我可以更普遍地谈论它，这就是我们生态系统中的大多数事情都会因为决定在那个山上死去的一些非常有动力的人，他们决定拿起旗帜并奔跑并实现它。
I almost started listing names of who's done things but if I do that then I'm going to leave
我几乎开始列出谁做的事情的名字，但是如果我这样做，那我就会离开
somebody out who was important and involved in it and I don't want to do that but just about all of
一个重要的人参与其中的人，我不想这样做，而是几乎所有
our major protocol changes and initiatives that are hard they get done because somebody decides
我们很难完成的主要协议更改和倡议，因为有人决定
that they are going to make it happen or some small number of people decide that they are going
他们将实现这一目标，或者少数人决定他们要去
to make it happen. And typically, that is a client team or somebody on a client team,
实现它。通常，那是客户团队或客户团队中的某人
because you don't really get to work directly on the protocol, not very effectively, without
因为您实际上并没有直接在协议上工作，而不是很有效，没有
being a client team, because client implementations matter so much. So I think for address-based
成为客户团队，因为客户实施非常重要。所以我认为基于地址的
expansion to happen, I think it means somebody is going to have to decide that that's a hill
扩展发生，我认为这意味着有人必须决定那是山丘
that they want to die on, or not. Hopefully, we don't die on any of these hills, but that's the
他们想死于还是不死。希望我们不会在这些山丘上死，但这就是
metaphor. And so, you know, is state expiry up next? Is address space expansion up next? Are the
隐喻。因此，您知道，国家即将到来吗？接下来是地址空间扩展吗？是
things all unblocked, right? Vitalik's beautiful roadmap document really kind of lines things up
一切都没有阻碍，对吗？维塔利克（Vitalik）美丽的路线图文档确实有点努力
in dependency order. And so I'm not sure if address space expansion is fully unlocked yet.
按依赖顺序。因此，我不确定地址空间扩展是否已完全解锁。
I think the process of getting address space expansion across the line is
我认为使整个生产线扩展空间扩展的过程是
having a hundred conversations with a hundred different open source
与一百个不同的开源进行一百对话
projects that all are going to need to update their libraries and,
所有人都需要更新其图书馆的项目，
you know, support 32 byte addresses.
您知道，支持32个字节地址。
And whoever does this is going to have to figure out and lay the,
无论做到这一点的人都必须弄清楚并铺设
the pavement and the path forward for how we get from where we are today to
人行道和前进的道路，即我们从今天的位置到
like a viable address space expansion implementation.
就像可行的地址空间扩展实现一样。
So maybe not the most satisfying answer,
所以也许不是最令人满意的答案，
but that's what I've got for this.
但这就是我所拥有的。
I also see that we're at an hour,
我还看到我们有一个小时，
what are our time constraints today?
我们今天的时间限制是什么？
What's the?
什么是？
This is scheduled for 90 minutes,
这是安排90分钟的
so you got another 30 minutes to go.
所以您还有30分钟的路程。
Great.
伟大的。
And I think that's all the questions for now.
我认为这就是现在的所有问题。
Great, I got one more small one here
太好了，我在这里又有一个
it will talk about. And in the meantime, I'd be curious for people to kind of drop into
它将谈论。与此同时，我很好奇人们跌入
chat direction on what you want to hear about with portal network. Do you want to hear anything
聊天方向您想通过门户网络听到的内容。你想听任何东西吗
about it? Do you know about it? Do you know nothing about it? Kind of like what's your
关于它？你知道吗？你对此一无所知吗？有点像你
knowledge level, and are there specific areas that you'd like me to dive into?
知识水平，您是否希望我深入研究特定领域？
Cool.
凉爽的。
This last one is quite simple, log reform.
最后一个非常简单，对数改革。
Okay.
好的。
So there are these four opcodes that are all log opcodes in the EVM.
因此，有这四个Opcodes都是EVM中的日志opcodes。
And when EVM execution is going through, and one of these opcodes gets called,
当执行EVM执行时，这些Opcodes被调用时，
it often has a couple of pieces of data associated with it.
它通常有几个与之相关的数据。
And those pieces of data get hashed to form what we call topics.
这些数据片段被哈希形成了我们所谓的主题。
And the idea is, or the log itself ends up with a topic,
这个想法是，或者日志本身最终都以一个主题，
and then some of the data inside of it becomes a topic.
然后其中的一些数据成为一个话题。
So the structure of the log itself dictates kind of like the primary topic, and then all of the data elements in it result in topics as well.
因此，日志本身的结构决定了类似的主题，然后其中的所有数据元素也导致了主题。
So these things all get sort of like bundled up and stuck into a receipt that has this Bloom filter in it.
因此，这些东西都变得有点像捆绑在一起并粘在一个带有该绽放过滤器的收据中。
And the idea was, okay, and as a concrete example, an ERC-20 transfer has a specific topic associated with it.
好的，可以的想法是，作为一个具体的例子，ERC-20转移具有与之相关的特定主题。
So the idea is that somebody, lots of people actually, want to know about ERC-20 token transfers because tokens.
因此，想法是，实际上有很多人想知道ERC-20代币转移，因为令牌。
and the idea is that by that when you perform an erc20 token transfer in a compliant erc20
这个想法是，当您在符合符合的ERC20中执行ERC20代币转移时
contract it'll limit a log with a specific topic it gets included in the receipt it gets included
合同将限制包含在收据中的特定主题的日志
in this bloom filter and that by doing this thing we can make it easy for application
在这个花朵过滤器中，通过这样做，我们可以使应用程序容易
for applications to consume these events as they happen.
为了使这些事件发生在这些事件发生时。
The reality is that we have 19 million and growing,
现实是，我们有1900万，增长，
and I hope it's,
我希望是
really should have looked at the block number this morning.
今天早上应该看一下块号。
I don't pay close enough attention to these things.
我对这些事情没有足够的关注。
That we have this huge history of blocks
我们拥有巨大的块历史
and every one of those blocks
这些块中的每一个
is spitting out all of this stuff.
正在吐出所有这些东西。
And then clients, Ethereum clients, have all of these JSON RPC methods, Git logs, and all these – I'm not going to remember all of them, but there's all these methods that are supposed to allow you to query the entire history of all of these 19 million blocks about these topics.
然后，客户端客户端具有所有这些JSON RPC方法，GIT日志和所有这些 - 我不会记住所有这些方法所有这1900万个关于这些主题的街区。
and these events that happened.
以及发生的事件。
This sucks as a client developer.
这很糟糕，作为客户开发人员。
Doing this, querying this stuff
这样做，查询这些东西
across 19 million possible historical blocks,
在1900万个可能的历史街区中，
because these endpoints basically say
因为这些终点基本上说
across any amount of this data set,
在任何数量的数据集中，
you should be able to accurately query
您应该能够准确查询
and get, right, you should be able to,
然后，正确，您应该能够
I want to know about all the ERC-20 tokens,
我想知道所有ERC-20令牌，
the worst thing you could do is ask a client,
您能做的最糟糕的事情是问客户，
Please give me all ERC-20 token transfers from block 0 to block 19 million.
请给我所有ERC-20代币转移，从0块0到1900万块。
And again, these were mistakes that were made in theory.
同样，这些是理论上犯的错误。
I think it is reasonable to say that the JSON-RPC API for accessing logs was a mistake.
我认为可以合理地说，用于访问日志的JSON-RPC API是一个错误。
It has this unbounded, massive data set that it has to query
它具有无界的大量数据集，必须查询
and potentially return huge, huge, huge, massive amounts of data.
并有可能返回大量，庞大，大量数据。
it's a mess it's a it's a it's an unreasonable api to serve um the amount of work that clients
这是一团糟，这是一个不合理的API，可以为客户服务数量
have had to do to to continue serving this api is is is nasty um i don't know the deep specifics
必须要继续服务这个api是令人讨厌的嗯，我不知道深处的细节
of it but like geff has layers and layers of all of these bloom filters and indexes in order to be
其中，就像Geff一样，所有这些花过滤器和索引都有层和层
able to answer the questions that you ask it about historical logs and serving these endpoints is
能够回答您问的有关历史日志和服务这些终点的问题是
awful and sucks um so the proposal is we are not going to do this anymore it's real simple
糟糕而糟糕，所以提议是我们不再这样做了，这很简单
um there's a there's an eep in there uh i don't know what the schedule is on any of this um but
嗯，那里有一个EEP，我不知道这个时间表在任何一个，但是
but um all of this information about about whether an erc20 token transfer happened
但是所有这些有关是否发生ERC20代币转移的信息
topics, all of that stuff, we're basically looking to say,
主题，所有这些东西，我们基本上都想说，
we're just not going to do that anymore.
我们只是不再这样做了。
This is something that an external service can do.
这是外部服务可以做的事情。
If you really need application data,
如果您确实需要应用程序数据，
then build yourself some fancy EVM tooling
然后构建一些精美的EVM工具
that executes every block and monitors them
执行每个块并监视它们
as they get executed and detects the things
当他们被执行并检测到事物时
that you want to detect.
您想检测到。
So this is what log reform is.
因此，这就是日志改革。
It's it's just effectively removing the logging API.
它只是有效地删除了日志记录API。
I believe that touches just about every piece of the purge.
我相信这几乎触及了清除的每一部分。
Maybe the only piece I didn't touch is gas observability and gas mechanics, which have proven to be problematic.
也许我唯一没有触摸过的是气体可观察性和气体力学，事实证明是有问题的。
The reason for that is that within the EVM, you can observe how much gas there is.
原因是在EVM中，您可以观察到有多少气体。
And in allowing the code that is executing to observe the gas as it's going by, it means that people have written things, and I have written, deep history me wrote things, that were really specific about gas and gas schedule and how much gas the code was written for.
并且在允许执行的代码观察天然气时的代码时，这意味着人们已经写了东西，而我写了深刻的历史，我写了一些东西，这些东西确实针对气体和气体时间表以及多少天然气编写代码。
And it turns out that by making the gas observable, which in turn sort of encourages people to write code that functions on gas observability, it makes it really complicated for us to change the gas schedule.
事实证明，通过使气体可观察到，这反过来又鼓励人们编写有关气体可观察性起作用的代码，这使我们更加复杂的是改变气体时间表。
And changing the gas schedule, changing the cost of different opcodes and things is something that we just fundamentally need to be able to do.
改变汽油计划，改变不同的Opcodes和事物的成本是我们从根本上需要做的。
And so this is another one of those things that is getting cleaned up in the Ethereum object format work that is happening,
因此，这是在以太坊对象格式工作中清理的另一件事，正在发生，
is the removal of gas observability.
是去除气体可观察性。
That's everything.
就是一切。
All right, I think that's all of the purge things.
好吧，我认为这就是清除的所有东西。
So, let's see.
所以，让我们看看。
I see the question about old transaction types.
我看到有关旧交易类型的问题。
I believe what we're looking at there, and again, take this with a grain of salt, is that over time we've implemented multiple new transaction types, and there's this kind of overall effort where I think what we want to do is try to eventually unify that into kind of like one, hopefully, hopefully one, like final type of transaction
我相信我们在那里看的东西，然后再用一粒盐来服用，这是随着时间的流逝，我们实施了多种新交易类型，而且我认为我们想做的是这样的整体努力尝试最终将其统一成像，希望，希望像最终类型的交易一样
that fully captures all of the different types of functionality
完全捕获了所有不同类型的功能
that we'd like to be able to come in through a transaction,
我们希望能够通过交易进入
which at that point, we can, in theory,
从理论上讲，这一点，我们可以
discard the old original transaction types
丢弃旧的原始交易类型
and have one kind of modernized transaction.
并有一种现代化的交易。
All right, I'm going to move on to talk a bit about portal network.
好吧，我将继续谈论门户网络。
Don't know how much I'm going to need this, but I magically cleaned a whiteboard.
不知道我需要多少，但是我神奇地清洁了白板。
So,
所以，
What do we say here?
我们在这里说什么？
So what Portal is, it is a very specialized storage engine for Ethereum.
因此，哪个门户是以太坊的非常专业的存储引擎。
I'm not going to get in.
我不会进来。
I've got less than 20 minutes here, so I'm not going to get into the details.
我在这里不到20分钟，所以我不会详细介绍。
I have a bunch of talks on the Internet where I go, where I deep dive on this.
我在互联网上有很多演讲，我对此深入研究。
Um, and, and, and then this will be some like, kind of like short condensed version of that. Um, but portal is a very specialized storage engine, um, for Ethereum's data.
嗯，然后，这将有些像这样的简短凝结版本。嗯，但是Portal是以太坊数据的非常专业的存储引擎。
And the general idea was take a look at all of the data that you need to do things with Ethereum and then figure out how we can take that data and we've got this huge block of data.
一般的想法是看看您需要用以太坊做事的所有数据，然后弄清楚我们如何获取这些数据，并且我们拥有了这么大的数据块。
And this right here is a full node, right?
这是一个完整的节点，对吗？
And it's got some, you know, like one, I don't know,
而且有一些，就像一个人一样，我不知道，
like something like one terabyte of data.
就像一个数据的数据一样。
And the idea behind portal network is that we've got this whole protocol, right?
门户网络背后的想法是我们拥有整个协议，对吗？
Where at its root, right, we have like a block hash, right?
在哪里，对，我们有一个块哈希，对吗？
And under that block hash, we've got all these fields,
在那个块哈希下，我们拥有所有这些领域，
like the transactions route and the state route and things like that.
就像交易路线，州路线以及类似的事情一样。
And I'm not even going to get into Beacon Chain,
而且我什至不会进入信标连锁店，
but Beacon Chain has all of these routes and things and whatnot in it.
但是，信标连锁店拥有所有这些路线和事物以及其中的内容。
And the idea is that all of the data that you need to do things with Ethereum
这个想法是，您需要与以太坊一起做事需要的所有数据
is addressed in some way, right?
以某种方式解决，对吗？
That all of these blocks have a block hash
所有这些块都有一个块哈希
and that all of these blocks have a transaction route, which references some list of transactions.
所有这些块都有一条交易路线，其中引用了一些交易列表。
And all of these blocks have a state, a state route, which references some, some big tree of
所有这些区块都有一个状态，一个州路线，引用了一些
state data, right? And things like that. And it's all addressed in some way. And, and I say addressed,
状态数据，对吗？和这样的事情。所有这些都以某种方式解决了。而且，我说的是
maybe another way to say that it's cryptographically anchored, but it's, it's referenced,
也许是另一种说法是密码锚定的，但它已被引用，
And it is referenced in a way that if I give you back the right data, if you have one of these things, you can verify that I did indeed give you the right data.
并以某种方式引用的是，如果我给您正确的数据，如果您有这些内容之一，则可以验证我确实确实为您提供了正确的数据。
The idea behind portal network is we've got this distributed peer-to-peer network of nodes.
门户网络背后的想法是，我们已经拥有了分布式的点对点节点网络。
Why can't we take this thing and cut it up into a bunch of pieces and spread all of those pieces out in some intelligent, planned way that matches the retrieval patterns that people use for when they want to get at this data?
为什么我们不能将其拿出来，将其切成一堆碎片，并以某种智能的计划方式将所有这些作品散布，以符合人们想要获取这些数据时使用的检索模式？
so that rather than having a thousand full nodes that are hard to run,
因此，与其具有难以运行的一千个完整节点，不如
and this number maybe is always kind of like, I don't think it's actually going down,
而且这个数字也许总是有点像，我不认为它实际上是在下降，
but boy, is it not growing massively.
但是男孩，不是很大。
Instead of having this small number of full nodes that are heavy and hard to run,
而不是拥有少数重量且难以运行的完整节点，而是
What if we had a much bigger network of really smaller, simpler nodes that all held on to some piece of this, and maybe some of them hold on to bigger pieces or whatever, but that we take all of that and we spread it out and we put it in all of these different nodes?
如果我们拥有一个更大的网络，该网络的网络非常较小，更简单，这些网络都坚持其中的某些部分，也许其中一些节点可以坚持更大的碎片或其他任何东西，但是我们将所有这些都拿走了，我们将其分配给我们将其放在所有这些不同的节点中？
My phone is ringing. Apologies.
我的手机在响。道歉。
So, good time to thought break there.
因此，好时机想在那里破裂。
Another way to think about this is that in the current paradigm where we have full nodes, you essentially have filled my board.
考虑到这一点的另一种方法是，在当前有完整节点的范式中，您本质上已经填满了我的董事会。
You've got the client and the network, okay?
您有客户和网络，好吗？
In the current model, the client is very heavy, and the network is very light, okay?
在当前模型中，客户端非常重，网络很轻，好吗？
DevP2P, the network that all Ethereum nodes run off of, is a very simple protocol.
DevP2P是所有以太坊节点运行的网络，是一个非常简单的协议。
it has a bunch of RPC methods for retrieving pieces of data from all the clients of that network.
它具有许多RPC方法，可从该网络的所有客户端检索数据段。
All the clients of that network are full nodes, and all of the methods that it uses are very simple.
该网络的所有客户端都是完整的节点，并且它使用的所有方法都非常简单。
Give me this block.
给我这个障碍。
Give me this piece of state.
给我这个状态。
Give me these receipts.
给我这些收据。
So this is now, right?
所以现在，对吧？
And in portal, we want to say the client is light and the network is complex.
在Portal，我们想说客户端很轻，网络很复杂。
I'm not sure that's quite the right word.
我不确定这是正确的词。
But the idea is that I want to move all of the machinery.
但是这个想法是我想移动所有机械。
It's heavy because it sinks and it manages states and it executes blocks and things.
它很重，因为它会沉没并管理状态并执行块和事情。
And what I want to do and what I've done and what we are doing is we're shoving this stuff into the network itself. And we're saying the network, the network itself is a full node. And the individual clients, the sum of them are what make this up.
我想做的事情以及我所做的事情以及我们正在做的事情是，我们将这些东西推入网络本身。我们要说的是网络，网络本身是一个完整的节点。和个别客户，他们的总和就是这样。
So it's a harder thing to do it is a it is a more complex network to build it is a it's that but the endgame is that the net sum of the network is a full node, and not just a full node, but an archive node.
因此，要做的是一个更难的事情，它是一个更复杂的网络，它是一个，但最终游戏是网络的净值是一个完整的节点，而不仅仅是一个完整的节点，而是一个存档节点。
One big, global shared archive node is a truly distributed network, it's truly peer-to-peer, that exposes what the functionality of a full node is through the sum of many, many smaller lightweight clients.
一个真正的全球共享存档节点是一个真正的分布式网络，它是真正的点对点，它通过许多众多较小的轻量级客户端的总和来揭示完整节点的功能。
I don't know how else you do like clients in Ethereum.
我不知道您还如何喜欢以太坊的客户。
There are cool alternative ways, such as people have done things like the provable JSON-RPC and things like that, where you can get JSON-RPC responses back but have them proven locally.
有一些很酷的替代方法，例如人们做了诸如可证明的JSON-RPC之类的事情，类似的事情，您可以在其中获得JSON-RPC响应，但可以在本地证明它们。
But all of those, to the best of my knowledge, still depend on a full node that has access to the state being able to serve you whatever the debug get proof stuff is.
但是，据我所知，所有这些仍然取决于一个完整的节点，该节点能够访问国家能够为您服务的任何调试获得证明内容。
And this is still dependent on a full node, which means that those light clients, while great for things like browser context where, you know, I'm not trying to say that they're not bad, but they're not light clients.
这仍然取决于一个完整的节点，这意味着那些轻度客户虽然非常适合浏览器上下文之类的东西，您知道，我并不是要说它们还不错，但它们不是轻的客户。
Not exactly.
不完全是。
Not in the definition that I prefer, which is shouldn't we be building peer-to-peer solutions?
不是我喜欢的定义，我们不应该构建点对点解决方案？
I think that's the gist of kind of like my elevator pitch for portal, and now I'm going to look at Discord and see what people are asking for.
我认为这是我的电梯门户网站的要旨，现在我要看不和谐，看看人们在要求什么。
What proofs is a portal client expected to serve so it's not considered a leech or kicked off?
预计门户网站客户将提供什么证据，因此不被视为水ech或启动？
Um, um, so every piece of data that portal serves is cryptographically anchored and
嗯，嗯，所以门户服务提供的每个数据都是密码锚定的，并且
canonically proven. So, um, for a client in our network to store anything, um, it will always
典型证明。所以，嗯，对于我们网络中的客户存储任何东西，嗯，它将永远
guarantee through whatever proof mechanism is needed, um, to, to, to anchor itself to canonical
通过任何需要的证明机制来保证，以固定自身
canonicalness. And the reason for that is that we have to make sure that you can't put garbage
规范。原因是我们必须确保您不能放垃圾
data into our network. We need a network that has a fixed, growing, but fixed amount of, at any
数据进入我们的网络。我们需要一个具有固定，增长但固定量的网络
given time, there's a fixed set of data that is viable and provable and can be stored in
给定时间，有一组固定的数据可行且可证明，可以存储在
Poro network. And if you can't prove that it's canonical, then it can't be in the network.
Poro网络。而且，如果您无法证明它是规范的，那么它就不能在网络中。
Um, we also have designed all of our access patterns, uh, so that, uh, you know, things
嗯，我们还设计了我们所有的访问模式，呃，所以，呃，你知道，
are provable in the way that they are accessed.
以访问它们的方式可证明。
Um, so, so the serving and storing tends to be very simple, small data packets of here's
嗯，所以，食用和存储往往是非常简单的小数据包
a Merkel Patricia tree proof that this tree node is in a state route and that that state
默克尔·帕特里夏树（Merkel Patricia Tree）证明了该树节点在州路线中，该状态
route is part of, of the canonical chain.
路线是规范链的一部分。
um the nuances of how that grows over time are a big unknown at this point and they are problem
嗯，随着时间的流逝，这种细微差别在这一点上是一个很大的未知数，这是问题
there there are many many problems that we expect to have to solve over time so think so questions
随着时间的流逝，我们期望有很多问题要解决，所以请考虑一下
and things like you know how much will you have to serve before you're kicked off or or you know
诸如您知道在开始之前必须提供多少服务或您知道的事情
what about leeching nodes and things like that we've generally kicked those cans down the road
那句子的节点和类似的东西呢
and said, these are going to be good problems for us to have, and these are going to be hard
并说，这些对于我们来说将是一个好问题，而这些问题将很难
problems that individual client teams are going to focus on solving. So the network itself is not
各个客户团队将专注于解决的问题。所以网络本身不是
likely to define specifics in terms of what a leecher is or how to protect yourself from being
可能根据leecher是什么或如何保护自己免受生存来定义细节
kicked off the network. And there really is no kicked off the network. It is a distributed peer
启动了网络。而且确实没有踢开网络。这是一个分布式的同行
to peer network that's permissionless. So there's not really a kicked off, but it is probably
无许可的同行网络。因此，没有真正的开始，但可能是
reasonable for some clients to implement protections where when they detect that a client
某些客户在检测到客户时实现保护的合理合理
maybe isn't doing their part through whatever metric, that maybe they either throttle them or
也许不是通过任何指标来竭尽所能
they stop serving data, or maybe there's even a meta layer that shows up where people,
他们停止提供数据，或者甚至还有一个元层显示了人们的位置
you know, some sort of like blacklisting or whitelisting or whatever.
您知道，某种像黑名单或白名单之类的。
But these are problems that we expect to solve, to have and solve down the road.
但是，这些是我们期望解决，解决并解决道路的问题。
In order to get this thing out the door, it is big, it is complicated, and we had to kind of cut scope.
为了把这东西弄出门，它很大，很复杂，我们必须切断范围。
And trying to launch on day one with a network that is fully secure from all of these different types and directions of attacks would mean that we would never, ever ship it.
试图在第一天通过一个网络启动，该网络完全可以从所有这些不同类型的攻击方向上确保，这意味着我们永远都不会发货。
um uh and so the follow-up question from Dirk here is like how much storage and bandwidth
嗯，所以德克的后续问题就像是多少存储和带宽
does a client need to participate will mobile phones be allowed to participate
客户是否需要参与将允许手机参与
I think the problem on mobile is going to be um I think mobile is possibly viable in some
我认为手机上的问题将会存在
limited context but we're going to have to see I think mobile is likely to be a relatively leachy
有限的背景，但我们必须看到我认为移动可能是一个相对浸出的
use case, because you don't want to spend your mobile bandwidth and your battery on serving a
用例，因为您不想将移动带宽和电池花在服务上
whole bunch of data, which means that your mobile thing is probably only going to participate in the
一堆数据，这意味着您的移动设备可能只参加
network during the times when you're actively using it, and it's going to probably get put
在您积极使用它的时候网络，它可能会得到
to sleep pretty quick as soon as you stop using it. But I still don't have an answer for your
停止使用时，要快速入睡。但是我仍然没有答案
question, because this is going to be a client-specific thing, and it's going to be something
问题，因为这将是特定于客户的事情，这将是一件事情
that we're going to have to essentially react to over time
随着时间的流逝，我们将不得不基本上对
as we see what the actual shape of these problems are,
当我们看到这些问题的实际形状是什么，
how big they are,
他们有多大，
and it's also probably a function
而且这可能也是一个功能
of how big our network actually ends up being.
我们的网络实际上有多大。
There's a chance that our network becomes big enough
我们的网络很有可能变得足够大
that we can absorb a good amount of leachy use cases,
我们可以吸收大量的浸出用例，
and there's a chance that clients will have to be smart
客户有可能必须变得聪明
and implement fast lanes and slow lanes
并实施快速车道和慢速车道
and things like that for leachy clients.
以及类似的东西。
Seven minutes left.
还剩七分钟。
I'm happy to answer more questions,
我很高兴回答更多问题，
but I don't think that there's an effective level of depth
但是我认为没有有效的深度
that I'm going to get into here in terms of like...
我将以像...
So, yeah, you mentioned early in the talk that you guys had recently, you know, passed a specific sort of like marker where, you know, you smash enough bugs and that you're ready to start serving data.
所以，是的，您在谈话的早期提到了你们最近通过了一种特定的标记，在那里，您知道，您砸碎了足够的错误，并且准备好开始提供数据。
Can you talk a little bit more about that and how a person might participate in the network and what you would want people to, you know, be?
您能否谈谈这一点，以及一个人如何参与网络，以及您希望人们成为什么样的人？
Yeah.
是的。
Yeah. How do they participate?
是的。他们如何参加？
it? So, um, one of the things that you could do today is run a bridge. So bridge is our term for
它？因此，嗯，您今天可以做的一件事就是跑一座桥。所以桥是我们的术语
clients that, that, that magically inject content into the network. So, um, I believe there's a blog
客户的客户神奇地将内容注入网络。所以，嗯，我相信有一个博客
post up on the portal network blog. That's is something like blog.eathportal.net. Maybe
在门户网络博客上发布。那就是blog.eathportal.net。或许
somebody can find that and drop it into the chat. Um, I think there's a recent blog post about
有人可以找到它并将其放入聊天中。嗯，我认为有一篇有关的博客文章
running a four-fours bridge, things rot quickly. So I hope that all of those things work. And if
跑四四个桥，东西很快腐烂。因此，我希望所有这些事情都起作用。如果
they don't, please tell us. But right now, running a bridge is one of the ways where you can actually
他们没有，请告诉我们。但是现在，跑桥是您实际上可以的一种方式之一
contribute and help to the network by helping us inject all of that historical four-fours data
通过帮助我们注入所有历史四四个数据来为网络做出贡献和帮助
into the network. Running a client is actually, if you'd like to run one, that sounds great. But
进入网络。如果您想运行一个客户，那听起来很棒。但
but I would ask that maybe you don't run a whole bunch of them behind NATed firewalls at the moment.
但是我要问的是，也许您目前没有在Nated Firewalls后面运行其中一堆。
We have a roadmap item that we just have intentionally deprioritized at the moment
我们有一个路线图项目，目前我们只是故意剥夺了路线图
because we're not quite ready to onboard people users.
因为我们还没有准备好加入人员用户。
We're definitely ready to onboard infrastructure users
我们肯定准备好加入基础架构用户
and people who want to run things in data centers and things like that,
想要在数据中心和类似事物中运行事情的人，
but we don't have a solid NAT traversal.
但是我们没有扎实的NAT遍历。
So, so, so I guess what I'm saying is that, like, I'd love for you guys to run a portal client, but we aren't actually actively marketing that at the moment, specifically because adding a large number of NATed nodes to our network is actually problematic. And we have, we have roadmap plans for how to deal with that, but they just haven't been done yet.
所以，所以，我想我的意思是，就像，我希望你们能够经营门户客户，但目前我们并没有积极地营销，特别是因为添加了大量我们网络的新节点实际上是有问题的。而且我们有，我们有有关如何处理的路线图计划，但是它们还没有完成。
Um, if you are working on a client, if you are working on a client team, um, if you, um, run a, if you, if you're interested in being kind of like leading edge experimental stuff, that's where we're at.
嗯，如果您正在为客户工作，那么如果您在客户团队中工作，嗯，如果您，嗯，如果您有兴趣像前沿实验性的东西，那就是我们're。
and we have four-fours data.
我们有四个四个数据。
Later this year, we'll have state data for you.
今年晚些时候，我们将为您提供状态数据。
And that's really like the golden hymn,
那真的就像是金色的赞美诗一样，
the magic hymn that lays golden eggs point
产卵点的魔术赞美诗
where we'll really start looking at user onboarding
我们在哪里真正开始查看用户入职
and where the interesting use cases show up.
以及有趣的用例出现的地方。
Right now, we're four-fours use cases, history use cases.
目前，我们四四个用例，历史案例。
If you want history data, we've got it for you.
如果您想要历史数据，我们已经为您准备了它。
We're ready to serve it for you.
我们准备为您服务。
Running a portal client and portal clients have,
运行门户网站客户端和门户网站客户端，
most of them should have some API for a standard looking JSON RPC API for fetching historical
他们中的大多数应该有一些API，用于标准的JSON RPC API，以获取历史
blocks. And you can experiment with what it is to fetch historical block data from portal network.
块。您可以尝试从门户网络获取历史块数据是什么。
So that's where we're at. And yeah, the thing I said earlier about things starting to work
这就是我们所处的位置。是的，我之前说的事情开始起作用
was that we've built this, you know, our clients are complex machines and they had some bugs in
是我们已经建造了这个，我们的客户是复杂的机器，他们有一些错误
them. We had a whole bunch of pieces that we put together and there were bugs that were keeping
他们。我们有一大堆我们放在一起的碎片，有些虫子一直在保留
clients from just staying online, memory leaks, things like that.
仅在线停留，内存泄漏等客户。
Those are boring software problems.
这些是无聊的软件问题。
And my team's essentially recently hit the bottom.
我的团队的本质上是最近的最低点。
You know, they've been pulling on that thread for a while,
你知道，他们已经在那个线程上拉了一段时间
and they hit the bottom, and everything just sort of started working.
他们碰到了底部，一切都开始工作了。
So we've got, like, 100% on latest block data, most recent block data,
因此，我们在最新块数据（最近的块数据）上有100％的数据，
and we are just actively piping all of the old historical blocks
而且我们只是在积极吹牛
into the network.
进入网络。
And I think we're looking at right now like a two-week timeframe to essentially hit what is 99.9% of all Ethereum block data being reliably available on the network.
而且我认为我们现在正在寻找一个为期两周的时间范围，从本质上击中了网络上所有以太坊块数据的99.9％。
Awesome.
惊人的。
Nimbus.
雨云。
I got a big dog.
我有一只大狗。
That's called Nimbus.
那就是尼布斯。
It is called Nimbus.
它被称为Nimbus。
He's a giant white fluffy cloud.
他是一个巨大的白色蓬松云。
He's not named after the Ethereum client.
他不是以以太坊客户命名的。
The client is named after him.
客户以他的名字命名。
The client's named after him, definitely.
当然，客户以他的名字命名。
Great.
伟大的。
Yeah, thank you so much.
是的，非常感谢。
I want to say congrats on all the progress with Portal.
我想恭喜Portal的所有进展。
It sounds very exciting.
听起来很令人兴奋。
I think we are running others.
我认为我们正在经营别人。
Some more questions in the Discord.
不和谐中还有一些问题。
Yeah, will there be Portal exports for other chains,
是的，其他连锁店会有门户出口吗？
like Layer 2s?
喜欢第2层？
Because they also need a data availability key.
因为他们还需要一个数据可用性密钥。
Ah, yes.
啊，是的。
I have a quick answer for that.
我有一个快速的答案。
So L2s are on my long horizon roadmap.
因此，L2在我漫长的地平线路线图上。
The thing about Portal is it is a critical mass system.
关于门户网站的问题是它是一个临界质量系统。
So the current Ethereum network works great if there's just one full node, right?
因此，如果只有一个完整的节点，那么当前的以太坊网络效果很好，对吗？
There's just like one full node out there to serve data.
就像一个完整的节点一样，可以提供数据。
Portal needs a critical mass of nodes to be able to store all of it.
门户需要大量的节点来存储所有节点。
And so running portal for test nets is just fundamentally not something that we are doing.
因此，从根本上讲，运行测试网的门户网站不是我们正在做的事情。
We have ideas about how to do it.
我们有关于如何做的想法。
But to run portal for a test net probably means us throwing 10 nodes at it that we run ourselves that are all massive instead of a bunch of tiny nodes.
但是，要运行一个测试网的门户网站可能意味着我们向其中投掷10个节点，我们自己运行的都是巨大的，而不是一堆小节点。
So portal needs a critical mass to work.
因此，门户需要一个临界质量才能工作。
And so if we want to do portal for an L2, that's great, but there has to be a critical mass of nodes being run to be able to serve the capacity, to achieve the overall capacity needed to serve that data, right?
因此，如果我们想为L2提供门户网站，那就很棒了，但是必须有大量的节点可以运行以达到能力，以达到服务于该数据所需的总体能力，对吗？
for main net for archive what we're talking about is what will like like late this year early next
对于档案的主要网络，我们要谈论的是下一年初的样子
year i'm not you know timelines are fuzzy but late this year early next year what you're likely to
那一年，我不是你知道时间表是模糊的，但是今年年末，您可能会有什么可能
see out of us is something that looks like a fundraising drive but it's going to be a storage
从我们身上看到的东西看起来像是筹款活动，但这将是一个存储
raising drive of of we've done all the work we we're ready for you to bring your nodes online
提高我们已经做好了所有我们准备的工作，以便您将节点带到网上
We're ready for consumer nodes that live behind NATs. Go turn your node on, configure it with however much storage you want to throw at us. That's great. And the wonderful thing about our network is that we can actually look at the network and see how much storage there is out there. We can derive it from the node information that's on the network.
我们已经为生活在NAT后面的消费者节点做好了准备。打开您的节点，并使用要向我们扔的多大存储配置。那太棒了。我们网络的奇妙之处在于，我们实际上可以查看网络，看看那里有多少存储空间。我们可以从网络上的节点信息中得出它。
And we're going to essentially run a storage drive for the Ethereum community to provide us with something like 200 terabytes of storage for us to throw at all of the Ethereum state data to bring on the single global archive node that absolutely everybody in the world can access.
而且，我们将实质上为以太坊社区提供一个存储驱动器，以向我们提供200多个存储的东西，以便我们在所有以太坊状态数据中投入到所有每个人的全球档案节点，以实现世界上每个人的单个全球档案节点可以访问。
So, you know, that'll be, we're not there yet, but we're chipping away at it.
因此，您知道，那会，我们还不到那儿，但是我们正在努力。
Yeah, it's amazing. I'm looking very much looking forward to this. I'm excited to participate for a while.
是的，太神奇了。我非常期待这一点。我很高兴参加一段时间。
I'm hearing about it work and especially like, yeah, what you're saying, like the community need to embrace it.
我听说它起作用，尤其是是的，您的意思是，就像社区需要拥抱它一样。
And I like what you said about the the submit task protocol before it's having it's like social layer.
而且，我喜欢您对提交任务的说法，就像社交层一样。
This like I imagine, you know, the torrent trackers kind of think where we can score ourselves and just contribute to that work.
就像我想象的那样，您知道，洪流跟踪器可以思考我们可以在哪里得分并为这项工作做出贡献。
I'm very excited to join that.
我很高兴能加入。
So yeah, we are out of time.
是的，我们没有时间。
I'm not sure if we want to push any longer.
我不确定我们是否要再推。
I think we should wrap up here.
我认为我们应该在这里结束。
I need to move on to my next thing.
我需要继续下一件事。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
是的，是的。
There are some questions in Discord.
不和谐中有一些问题。
Maybe if you join there,
也许如果你加入那里，
then for later, but...
然后以后...
I will page through this later today
我将在今天晚些时候通过
when I have a bit more time.
当我有更多时间。
And if there are questions that I didn't get to,
如果有我没有解决的问题，
I will more than happily answer them in this thread.
我将在这个线程中高兴地回答它们。
Awesome. Yeah, thank you very much, Piper. It was it was amazing. I love the whiteboard
惊人的。是的，非常感谢，派珀。真是太神奇了。我爱白板
and all of the explanation. I learned a lot. I saw your talks in portal network and I learned
以及所有解释。我学到了很多。我在门户网络中看到了您的演讲，我学会了
even more today. So it's it's really great. And yeah, thank you so much for for being
今天甚至更多。所以这真的很棒。是的，非常感谢您
here. It's it's an honor as always.
这里。这是一如既往的荣誉。
Very happy to be happy to do it.
很高兴能做到这一点。
Thanks, Piper. And everybody who's watching. We'll see you all next Monday for a talk on
谢谢吹笛者。每个人都在看。我们将在下周一见到大家
pre images. Thanks.
预图像。谢谢。
Oh, break and piles.
哦，休息和堆。
Break and piles.
休息和堆。
Yeah.
是的。
The calendar says pre-images.
日历显示前图像。
Well, I did that.
好吧，我做到了。
It was by mistake.
这是错误的。
Pre-images from get.
GET的前图像。
¶¶
¶¶
Thank you.
谢谢。